<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>sef.kloninger.com</title><link>http://sef.kloninger.com/</link><description>None</description><atom:link href="http://sef.kloninger.com/rss.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 07:34:27 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Perspective</title><link>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/petrol-car.html</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right; padding-left:15px;"&gt;
    &lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"&gt;
        &lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Test drive of a petrol car - &lt;a href="http://t.co/lPQ0xcs7uU"&gt;http://t.co/lPQ0xcs7uU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— sefk (@sefk) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sefk/status/595318498894553088"&gt;May 4, 2015&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right when I was thinking about writing a post about much we overlook
the sins of the status quo, some Swedes
&lt;a href="http://teslaclubsweden.se/test-drive-of-a-petrol-car/"&gt;took care of it for me&lt;/a&gt;. Tack vänner!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tear around town carrying gallons of incendiary liquid just inches
beneath my beloved family? 
In a mode of transport that &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_motor_vehicle_deaths_in_U.S._by_year"&gt;kills upwards of thirty thousand Americans every year&lt;/a&gt;? 
Sure, that's fine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/petrol-car.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 07:05:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Lessons from Three Years in AWS</title><link>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/aws.html</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="float:right" class="postimage" src="http://sef.kloninger.com/f/aws.png" alt="AWS Logo" width="30%"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've spent the last three years building and operating web sites
with Amazon Web Services and here are a few lessons I've learned. 
But I first have to come clean that I'm a fan of AWS with only
casual experience with other IAAS/PAAS platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S3 Is Amazing&lt;/strong&gt;. They made the right engineering choices and
compromises: cheap, practically infinitely scalable, fast enough,
with good availability. $0.03/GB/mo covers up for a lot of sins.
Knowing it's there changes how you build systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IAM Machine Roles From The Start&lt;/strong&gt;. IAM with &lt;a href="http://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSEC2/latest/UserGuide/ec2-instance-metadata.html"&gt;Instance Metadata&lt;/a&gt;
is a powerful way to manage secrets and rights. Trouble is you can't add
to existing machines. Provision with machine roles in big categories
(e.g. app servers, utility machines, databases) at the start, even if 
just placeholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Availability Zoness Are Only Mostly Decoupled&lt;/strong&gt;. After the 2011
&lt;a href="http://www.networkworld.com/article/2202805/cloud-computing/amazon-ec2-outage-calls--availability-zones--into-question.html"&gt;us-east-1 outage&lt;/a&gt; we were reassured that a coordinated 
outage wouldn't happen again, but it happened again just
&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/aws/comments/2zpag7/aws_internal_dns_outage/"&gt;last month&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They Will Lock You In And You'll Like It&lt;/strong&gt;. They secondary services
work well, are cheap, and are handy. I'm speaking of SQS, SES,
Glacier, even Elastic Transcoder. Who &lt;em&gt;wants&lt;/em&gt; to run a durable queue
again?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CloudFormation No&lt;/strong&gt;. It's tough to get right. My
objection isn't programming in YAML, I don't mind writing Ansible plays, it's the
complexity/structure of CloudFormation that is impenetrable. Plus
even if you get it working once, you'd never run it again on something
that is running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boto Yes&lt;/strong&gt;. Powerful and expressive. Don't script the CLI, use
Boto. Easy as pie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Qualify Machines Before Use&lt;/strong&gt;. Some VMs have lousy networking,
presumably due to a chatty same-host or same-rack neighbor. Test
for loss and latency to other hosts you own and on EBS. (I've used
home-grown scripts, don't know of a standard open-source widget,
someone should write one).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VPC Yes&lt;/strong&gt;. If you have machines talking to each other (i.e. not a
lone machine doing something lonely) then put them in a VPC. It's not
hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NAT No&lt;/strong&gt;. You think that'll improve security, but it will just
introduce SPOFS and capacity chokepoints. Give your machines publicly
routable IP's and use security groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Network ACLs Are A Pain&lt;/strong&gt;. Try to get as far as you can with just security
groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You'll Peer VPC's Someday&lt;/strong&gt;. Choose non-overlapping subnet IP ranges
at the start. It's hard to change later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spot Instances Are Tricky&lt;/strong&gt;. They're only For a very specific use
case that likely isn't yours. Setting up a test network? You can
spend the money you save by using spot on swear jar fees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pick a Management Toolset&lt;/strong&gt;. Ansible, Chef, all those things aren't
&lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; that different when it comes down to it. Just don't dither back
and forth. There's a little bit of extra Chef love w/ AWS but not enough to tip
the scales in your decision I'd reckon. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tech Support Is Terrible&lt;/strong&gt;. My &lt;a href="http://www.wavefront.com/"&gt;last little
startup&lt;/a&gt; didn't get much out of the &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/premiumsupport/"&gt;business level tech
support&lt;/a&gt; we bought. We needed it so we could call in to get
help when we needed it, and we used that for escalating some problems.
It was nice to have a number to call when I urgently need to up a
system limit, say. But debugging something real, like a networking
problem? Pretty rough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;...Unless You Are Big&lt;/strong&gt;. Stanford, on the other hand, had a named
rep who was responsive and helpful. I guess she was sales, but I
used her freely on support issues and she worked the backchannels
for us. Presumably this is what any big/important customer would
get, that's just not you, sorry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Real Power Is On Demand&lt;/strong&gt;. I'm reaffirming cloud
koolaid here. Running this way lets you build and run systems
differently, &lt;em&gt;much better&lt;/em&gt;. I've relied on the cloud this to bring
up emergency capacity. I've used it to convert a class of machines
on the fly to the double-price double-RAM tier when hitting a
surprising capacity crunch. There are a whole class of problems
that get much easier when you can have 2x the machines for just a
little while.  When someone comes to you with that cost/benefit
spreadsheet arguing why you should self-host, that's when you need
your file of "the cloud saved my bacon" stories at the ready.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Tech</category><guid>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/aws.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 07:10:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Don't Say No By Email</title><link>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/saying-no.html</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="float:right" class="postimage" src="http://sef.kloninger.com/f/frown.png" alt=":(" width="192" height="178"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I have to tell someone no, I pick up the phone. I &lt;strong&gt;hate&lt;/strong&gt;
talking on the phone, but I do it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you're answering no to someone, you're disappointing them even
if just a little bit. So you owe it to them to talk instead of
sending an email. It's the polite thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there are two other reasons, selfish reasons, for making the
call. First, you get immediate feedback on how they took the news.
If they're upset then you can do damage control straight away. And
at least you know! And second, delivering bad news directly and
respectfully is an important skill to develop. We can all use the
practice. And it's never as bad as I think it will be.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Life</category><guid>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/saying-no.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2015 01:08:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fewer Trick or Treaters This Year</title><link>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/halloween-2014.html</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year's Halloween tally was 208.  I don't know why we have 32%
fewer trick-or-treaters than we had last year, which was down 20%
from the year before that.  Maybe the rain earlier in the day kept
people home.  Maybe because it was Friday people opted for parties
instead of going door to door.  I don't know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script type="text/javascript" src="//ajax.googleapis.com/ajax/static/modules/gviz/1.0/chart.js"&gt;
{"dataSourceUrl":"//docs.google.com/spreadsheet/tq?key=0AnpKmkglpRs5dDh3dWRmRlFVaG0yc08xU0lhTzF1NUE&amp;transpose=1&amp;headers=0&amp;range=C20%3AH21&amp;gid=9&amp;pub=1","options":{"titleTextStyle":{"bold":true,"color":"#000","fontSize":"24"},"series":{"0":{"color":"#b45f06"}},"animation":{"duration":500},"width":600,"hAxis":{"useFormatFromData":true,"title":"","minValue":null,"viewWindowMode":null,"textStyle":{"bold":true,"color":"#222","fontSize":"20"},"viewWindow":null,"maxValue":null},"vAxes":[{"useFormatFromData":true,"title":"","minValue":0,"viewWindowMode":"explicit","textStyle":{"bold":true,"color":"#222","fontSize":"20"},"logScale":false,"viewWindow":{"min":0,"max":null},"maxValue":null},{"useFormatFromData":true,"minValue":null,"logScale":false,"viewWindow":{"min":null,"max":null},"maxValue":null}],"booleanRole":"certainty","title":"Trick or Treaters, Menlo Park, CA","height":240,"legend":"none","useFirstColumnAsDomain":true,"isStacked":false,"tooltip":{}},"state":{},"view":{},"isDefaultVisualization":false,"chartType":"ColumnChart","chartName":"Chart 4"}
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to my friend Stuart for being on this year's data gathering
crew.  As usual, the full story is 
&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/ccc?key=0AnpKmkglpRs5dDh3dWRmRlFVaG0yc08xU0lhTzF1NUE"&gt;in the numbers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Halloween</category><guid>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/halloween-2014.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 09:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>In Praise of the Hand Tally</title><link>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/hand-tally.html</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="float:right" class="postimage" src="http://sef.kloninger.com/f/tallies.jpg" alt="Tally Marks" width="height=174"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past five years I've gathered statistics on how many
trick-or-treaters have come by on Halloween.  If you want to read
about that, check out posts from &lt;a href="http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/201311halloween-2013.html"&gt;last year&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/201210halloween-candy-data.html"&gt;the year before&lt;/a&gt;.
This post is about &lt;strong&gt;how&lt;/strong&gt; I track those stats, and how I don't.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every year I'm tempted to build some fancy system to collect and
manage these statistics.  Wouldn't it be fun, say, to wire up some
Raspberry Pi sensor that automatically counts and tweets running
totals?  It wouldn't be &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; hard and sounds like fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is making something like that reliable.  You'd have to
do all the un-fun stuff, like testing and contingency planning.  If
your baseline is a clipboard, paper, and a ball point pen, your bar
for failure is basically "never".  Even if I did build something
fancy I'd still end up doing backup tallies by hand.  At this human
scale, the tech ends up being a fun gimmick, not required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It reminds me of a story from friend [Tony].  Tony
and his brother &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ProtomCannon"&gt;Tom&lt;/a&gt; run a giant gaming convention every year,
the &lt;a href="http://evo.shoryuken.com/"&gt;Evolution Championship Series&lt;/a&gt; (Evo for short).  It's a
multi-day convention in Las Vegas that attracts something like ten
thousand participants.  They run the whole thing with their two
other founders and some friends — I'm sure they have some
paid help now, but the four guys are the main ones.  It's impressive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="center"&gt;
&lt;img src="http://evo.shoryuken.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/9450177474_3d2e293e9d_b.jpg" style="padding-top:20px; padding-bottom:20px"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that Tony and Tom are strong engineers, I figured this would
be a slick high-tech operation.  Not so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tony said they've tried tech at various points and it wasn't worth
it.  It's easy to see why that is tempting: they have multiple
mobile coordinators that need access to changing, shared information,
like brackets and schedules.  But what they've tried has let them
down.  Usually it's not the hard parts that fail, but the basics,
like batteries and wireless connectivity.  So they still run this
off of printouts and voice communications (cell phones/walkie-talkies)
and periodic data dumps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so, this year I'll be gathering my Halloween stats like I always
have: clipboard, pen, and a hand-held &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/STEELMASTER-Counter-Inches-Silver-200100492/dp/B0089KJSFQ/ref=sr_1_3"&gt;tally counter&lt;/a&gt;.  The data
will still be timely and accurate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the curious few, check out my &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/ccc?key=0AnpKmkglpRs5dDh3dWRmRlFVaG0yc08xU0lhTzF1NUE"&gt;Halloween Traffic Spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two postscripts.  First, Please stop spreading that
&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LQy1DH38E5g"&gt;NASA Space Pen story&lt;/a&gt;.  I'm sure you've heard it: how do you write in zero G?
the wasteful Americans commissioned a multi-million dollar space
pen project; the scrappy can-do Russians used pencils.  Well, this
story has been &lt;a href="http://www.snopes.com/business/genius/spacepen.asp"&gt;debunked by the good people at Snopes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And second, I'd like to plug Tony and Tom's "day job", &lt;a href="http://stonehearth.net/"&gt;Stonehearth&lt;/a&gt;.
I think of it as Starcraft meets Minecraft.  I am so eager to play
it when it lands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Halloween</category><category>Tech</category><guid>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/hand-tally.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2014 16:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Leaving Stanford Online Ed</title><link>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/leaving-stanford.html</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p style="float:right; align:right; width:30%"&gt;&lt;img class="postimage" src="http://sef.kloninger.com/f/stanfordlogo.gif" alt="Stanford"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friday was my last day building Stanford's &lt;a href="https://class.stanford.edu/"&gt;open-source online education
platform&lt;/a&gt;.  What started as a lark turned out to be one of the most
fun and rewarding times in my career.  So I'll use this opportunity to
reflect back on the project and what we accomplished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;First a Little History&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;i&gt;
    "MOOCs are just information technology happening to higher education."  
    -- George Siemens
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I joined Stanford in 2012, coming off of my self-imposed &lt;a href="http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/201204my-sabbatical.html"&gt;sabbatical&lt;/a&gt;.
My goal then had been to get hands-on again, to sharpen the technical
tools.  I did a few online classes and hobby projects, but my friend Jane
suggested I could do some good and have more fun working in a group back
on the Stanford campus (I'm an alum, after all).  So I joined her and a
small group of engineers in a conference room in the fourth floor of
&lt;a href="http://www-cs.stanford.edu/info/gates"&gt;Gates&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall what was happening in &lt;a href="http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/201207on-line-education.html"&gt;education in 2012&lt;/a&gt;.  Stanford's
&lt;a href="https://www.udacity.com/course/cs271"&gt;first&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.coursera.org/course/ml"&gt;three&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://class.stanford.edu/courses/Home/Databases/Engineering/about"&gt;big&lt;/a&gt; Massive Open Online Courses (MOOCs) had
just made big splashes.  Later that year the New York Times would famously
declare 2012 to be the &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/11/04/education/edlife/massive-open-online-courses-are-multiplying-at-a-rapid-pace.html"&gt;Year of the MOOC&lt;/a&gt;.  What could consumer-grade
web tech could do for higher education?  Or even &lt;em&gt;do to&lt;/em&gt; higher ed?  The
low cost and ease of cloud computing removed many of the barriers to trying
new things out.  You approach experimentation completely differently when
things get 100x or 1000x cheaper.  Profs were literally getting out their
credit cards and buying Wordpress blogs or throw up virtual machines for
automated grading.  Wild stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this was the environment when I joined Stanford.  That first summer we
built &lt;a href="https://class2go.stanford.edu/"&gt;Class2Go&lt;/a&gt; to host free online courses.  We went from empty
buffers to a live Python/Django site for hundreds of thousands of enrolled
students in eleven weeks.  Man, that was a fun ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We built Class2Go for a few reasons.  First, we feel strongly that Stanford
needs to control its destiny.  There is no "file format" for online ed
content, so every course development online is a bet on a platform.  And
we didn't want to be beholden to one platform vendor (still don't).  In
2012 the technology that had powered the early MOOCs were becoming "platforms"
and moving off-campus.  While we were happy with the success of Udacity,
Coursera, and (a year later later) NovoEd, we were also a bit wary.  They were
going to have to repay their investors at some point.  The last thing we
wanted was for online education to look like textbook publishing or academic
journals.  We know what happened there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, we wanted to have a broad impact.  We were lucky enough to have
an engineering team at Stanford, but it makes no sense for every school
to develop their own platforms.  This kind of project is tailor made for
open source development, and I've advocated strongly for that since the
beginning.  Not only would this mean many others could benefit form the
software, Stanford would benefit from many more developers and see many
more use cases (and we have).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the third reason is the need to modify the platform.  There are many
reasons why you need to get hands dirty in the code.  It could be just
developing a point feature, like &lt;a href="https://github.com/edx/edx-ora2/pull/620"&gt;tracking changes in peer evaluation&lt;/a&gt;.
Or it could enable a whole new use case, like &lt;a href="https://github.com/edx/edx-platform/pull/67"&gt;authenticating
on-campus students&lt;/a&gt;.  Our teachers and researchers want to do
interesting work online, not just put up courses.  They have great ideas
about using the things that make MOOCs unique (different cultures, scale,
data-gathering, etc.) as powerful tools, not obstacles to overcome.  (To
hear more about interesting online ed projects, follow the Stanford VPOL 
&lt;a href="http://signalblog.stanford.edu/"&gt;Signal Blog&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Scaling Up With EdX&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come early 2013 we started seeing some interest from others to use Class2Go
outside Stanford.  While exciting, we were concerned about the quality of
the code.  There were giant missing features that were going to be hard
to write (e.g. peer evaluation).  And the code was quick and dirty,
with nearly zero tests and other things a "real project" needs.  We could
have backfilled all of that, but it sounded like a lot of work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's around that time that we started talking with edX.  Our academic ties
to MIT, Harvard, and other edX consortium members are strong.  We liked
their philosophy and approach.  And our technologies were similar: both
Python/Django stacks running in Amazon, etc.  We decided to work together.
&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/robvrubin"&gt;Rob Rubin&lt;/a&gt; and I got the deal done quickly, mostly between sessions
at PyCon.  In April 2013 we &lt;a href="http://news.stanford.edu/news/2013/april/edx-collaborate-platform-030313.html"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that we'd shutter Class2Go
and adopt the Open edX platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stanford didn't join the XConsortium.  Rooted in our belief in the power
of open source, we made open-sourcing their platform a condition of us
working together.  EdX didn't need convincing.  But Stanford was of
a forcing function to do it then, and it did take some work.  They &lt;a href="http://ostatic.com/blog/edx-open-sources-its-super-influential-online-learning-platform"&gt;pushed
the button&lt;/a&gt; on June 1 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past year and a half the Stanford team has operated as a virtual
member of the extended edX engineering team.  They've been a fun group to
work with, generous with their time and good collaborators.  We've been
running the platform successfully now for over a year, supporting dozens
of courses for Stanford students, MOOCs, online high school students, and
many other uses.  We've contributed back many features, like theming,
course email, instructor analytics to name a few.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've spent a lot of my own time helping to make sure the Open edX project
a healthy open source project.  It's not enough to just open up the code,
to have a thriving community you have to conduct your development out in
the open.  Beyond helping other institutions get up and running I've worked
to drive the open-source agenda overall.  With my friend &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/natea"&gt;Nate Aune&lt;/a&gt;
last May we &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/msg/edx-code/DRqcLlMKhgs/KBvzBj13hQ8J"&gt;published recommended changes&lt;/a&gt; to technology, governance,
and community.  And with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/podehaye"&gt;Paul-Olivier Dehaye&lt;/a&gt; this past June we
hosted the first &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/msg/edx-code/EqVUkvovq0k/e2Be2fo5QJUJ"&gt;Open edX workshop&lt;/a&gt;, in Zürich.  I think those efforts
have made a difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Moving On&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've heard the siren's song of the startup.  Last Friday August 29th was
my last day at Stanford.  I'll post about my &lt;a href="http://www.wavefront.com/"&gt;next gig&lt;/a&gt; when the time
is right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I do feel good about moving on.  The Stanford engineering team is solid
and productive.  The engineers work well with each other and have a good
breadth of skills.  The course operations team is dedicated and strong.
&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jinpa1345"&gt;Jane Manning&lt;/a&gt; will do great running the team in addition to her day
job as of product management -- she's done this before and knows the product
inside and out.  And &lt;a href="https://github.com/jbau"&gt;Jason Bau&lt;/a&gt;, the Stanford Open edX tech lead,
will continue to anchor eng and ops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what about the open source community?  I do feel like the flywheel is
starting to spin up.  EdX is fostering this in several ways, I'll mention
two.  First, they are in the process of opening up their bug tracking
database and sprint planning (Jira).  That's a key step to doing true &lt;em&gt;open
development&lt;/em&gt;.  And second, I'm really excited to see the first full-on
&lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/msg/edx-code/bqASLi8FZjs/Eb6OQpHbevsJ"&gt;Open edX conference&lt;/a&gt; happening this upcoming November.  I expect
that to be well attended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EdX has asked me to continue on as a member of the Technical Advisory
Board, which I am happy and honored to do.  I look forward to staying
plugged into the project and working with my friends on the board (Armando,
Ike, Jim, Phil, Ross...)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to my many friends on the project: the Open edX engineering team,
especially Jason and Jane; the team in the Office of the Vice Provost for
Online Learning, especially Professor &lt;a href="http://theory.stanford.edu/people/jcm/"&gt;John Mitchell&lt;/a&gt; who made this
possible; and my many friends at edX.  There's a lot to be proud of over
the past two years, and a lot of good work ahead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Education</category><guid>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/leaving-stanford.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 06:45:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Arthroscopy Is Amazing</title><link>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/arthroscopy.html</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="float:right" class="postimage" src="http://sef.kloninger.com/f/sef-left-knee.png" alt="My Left Knee" width="30%"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three days ago I was hobbling around on a sore knee with a torn
meniscus. But after just three days of icing and Ibuprofen and
resting on the couch already my knee is almost better than it was
before. This arthroscopic surgery stuff is amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My knee had been getting progressively worse for the past few months.
But the clincher was six weeks ago, when I was chasing around a dog that
was loose in our front yard. A twist, pop, and I was down. The doctor
I saw the next day confirmed that it wasn't anything "serious" like a
torn ligament, but something was definitely wrong. When we went up to
a week of family camping a few weeks back, I couldn't go on any hikes
and could barely play ping pong. It was a real bummer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I met with a sports medicine doctor at Palo Alto Medical Foundation
and got an MRI. He saw a few things wrong in there. A few days later, I
was getting the procedure done. Viola. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterwards I was surprised that it didn't hurt. They did prescribe
some pain medication (Hydrocodone plus Acetaminophen) that I've
been taking when I go to bed, but haven't needed during the day.
I've been using a &lt;a href="http://www.djoglobal.com/products/donjoy/donjoy-iceman-clear3"&gt;machine that pumps ice water through a pad&lt;/a&gt;
around my knee all day to keep it cool, and that's worked really
well. &lt;strong&gt;So much better&lt;/strong&gt; than ice packs. Totally recommend the ice
machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the good surgical team at &lt;a href="http://www.pamf.org/sports/"&gt;Palo Alto Medical Foundation&lt;/a&gt;
especially &lt;a href="http://www.pamf.org/dr-colin-l-eakin.html"&gt;Dr. Colin Eakin&lt;/a&gt;. Their surgery center on Willow Road
made the whole experience smooth and reassuring. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But one pro tip for you out there considering this. Don't read the
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/General_anaesthesia"&gt;wikipedia article on General Anesthesia&lt;/a&gt; the night before
surgery. It's crazy stuff. Especially the parts about how we're
still not really sure how it works, or the part about how the level
of anesthesia where it is safe to operate is right between "excitement"
where you vomit and twitch, and "overdose" where you stop breathing.
Don't read that part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm back to work tomorrow, and I expect to be back on my bike by next
week!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Life</category><guid>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/arthroscopy.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 05:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>David Bowie To The Rescue</title><link>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/earworm.html</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p style="float:right; align:right; width:30%"&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Bowie_JohnDancing1.jpg#mediaviewer/File:Bowie_JohnDancing1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="postimage" src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/b/bb/Bowie_JohnDancing1.jpg" alt="Bowie JohnDancing1.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often wake up with a song going through my head. I don't know
why this happens. The stranger thing the songs. Yesterday
was good, I woke up to Led Zepplin's &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JjlJBmwF3PI"&gt;Immigrant Song&lt;/a&gt; —
what a great way to start the day. But earlier in the week it was
inexplicably the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KiQzUEc_FmI"&gt;Golden Girls Theme Song&lt;/a&gt;. Gah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've heard them called earworms: songs that get stuck in your head and
don't get out. So I'll share with you now the antidote, taught to
me by my good friend &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jinpa1345"&gt;Jane Manning&lt;/a&gt;.  Thanks, Jane!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sing David Bowie's song &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6VrqCBsbeuc"&gt;John, I'm Only Dancing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;
Not one of Bowie's better known songs, nor even one of his best, but
remarkably well suited to this. I believe it's because the
melody is kind of odd and not all that pleasant, so it's not going
to get stuck itself. You kind of remember the melody and lyrics,
but not quite, so that keeps you busy. It always does the trick. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Life</category><guid>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/earworm.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2014 00:25:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Feedback Without Tips</title><link>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/tips.html</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="float:right" class="postimage" src="http://sef.kloninger.com/f/tip-oneill.jpg" alt="Tip O'Neill" width="30%"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really don't like tipping. I'm not like &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Z-qV9wVGb38"&gt;Mr. Pink&lt;/a&gt;. It's
not that I don't want my server or driver to get something extra.
I just don't like the awkward social situation of deciding if this
is a tipping situation, and if so, how much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two services have come up recently where I will happily pay a premium
to not have to fret about too much or too little:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Uber&lt;/strong&gt;. Lots to like about this service but the act of just 
  leaving out of my cab without paying is joyful. I always rate 
  my drivers, good or bad. 98% of the time, it's good by the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OrderAhead&lt;/strong&gt;. Are you supposed to tip when picking up takeout 
  from a restaurant? I've never known. Neither way feels right, so 
  I usually end up splitting the difference and rounding up to 
  some amount, say leaving a 6% tip, which is the &lt;em&gt;worst&lt;/em&gt; choice. 
  Either that's 6% that wasn't expected, or I'm inadvertently
  shafting someone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both of these services decouple feedback from money. Both avoid
awkwardly changing money. I'd definitely pay a premium for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder what other service business would benefit from decoupling
feedback from money?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Tech</category><guid>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/tips.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2014 03:07:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>CS Students: Learn to Write</title><link>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/learn-to-write.html</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="float:right" class="postimage" src="http://sef.kloninger.com/f/writing-hand.jpeg" alt="Writing Hand" width="40%"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I could do my college years over I would focus on writing. I
would take courses that required a lot of writing, in the spirit
of "learn by doing". I'd also take courses in the mechanics and
craft: grammar, vocabulary, and rhetoric.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to consider myself a competent writer. And certainly good
enough for an engineer, right? But I've learned that I have a long
way to go. I've learned that engineers spend much more time writing
than you expect. And I appreciate how hard it is to write well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This came up just this past week. I came across a beautiful four
page essay. It laid out the problem, described alternatives, and
lead you concisely to a well-reasoned conclusion. Sure, it was about
technology, but what carried the day was the good writing. Humbling!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You're saying: but wait, you're a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pointy-Haired_Boss"&gt;pointy-haired boss&lt;/a&gt; now
Sef, one of those guys who doesn't do &lt;em&gt;Real Work&lt;/em&gt; anymore. You write
email and boss people around. I understand why managers like you
need to write, I'm an engineer. I write code. Well, there's some
truth to that. But I'd like to convince you that even monster coders,
if they're any good, write a lot, write well, and value good writing
in others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is rare for someone to do their work in isolation and have it
matter. Either you're working as part of a team, in a company or
a community of developers, say on an open-source project. Sure, you
build a great system or feature. But to have it matter to the world,
for others to adopt it, you need to document, publicize, support,
teach. 98% of that is writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a lunchtime conversation with &lt;a href="http://jacobian.org/writing/great-documentation/"&gt;Jacob Kaplan-Moss&lt;/a&gt;,
Django's co-founder, at last year's PyCon. I asked him why Django
caught on and was adopted by so many of us (including &lt;a href="http://class2go.stanford.edu/"&gt;my last
project&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://code.edx.org/"&gt;my current project&lt;/a&gt;). I was expecting him
to point to features or timing. Instead he said it was "because we
wrote good docs". The Django team didn't treat documentation as an
afterthought. They have lots of docs, and they are good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider that rare bird, the iconoclastic engineer working in
isolation on their own project. I'm thinking of &lt;a href="http://antirez.com/"&gt;Antirez&lt;/a&gt; or
&lt;a href="http://www.marco.org/"&gt;Marco&lt;/a&gt;. (Maybe they aren't even truly on their own so much.
Humor me!) They are prolific and strong coders. But they also write
a lot of words! They write a ton about their project; also tech
landscape and their place in it. Would their software have as much
of an impact if they didn't write so much (and well)? I say no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Case in point. Both Marco and I wrote blog posts riffing off the
same topic two weeks ago. First, read &lt;a href="http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/consume-produce-public.html"&gt;mine&lt;/a&gt;, then
&lt;a href="http://www.marco.org/2014/01/03/the-builders-high"&gt;his&lt;/a&gt;.  It takes me a ton of words to get something
basic out.  His is concise and clear. Sheesh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So kids, don't shortchange those liberal arts classes. It's not
fluffy stuff on the side. &lt;strong&gt;That is core&lt;/strong&gt;. You need to write well
to be a good engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protip: the best way to do this is to major in the humanities. They
write like crazy over there. Be like my friend Dan Chu and major
in history, but secretly take CS courses on the side. If you're
super smart like him, and can manage getting both degrees, then
you're awesome. But don't sacrifice the BA for the BS. I would
&lt;strong&gt;love&lt;/strong&gt; to talk to a candidate with with a History BA and a Computer
Science MS.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Tech</category><guid>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/learn-to-write.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2014 00:17:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>