<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sef.kloninger.com (Posts about Appreciation)</title><link>https://sef.kloninger.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://sef.kloninger.com/categories/appreciation.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:14:16 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Thanks, Daisy Disk</title><link>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/daisy-disk/</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="float:right" class="postimage" src="https://sef.kloninger.com/f/daisy-disk-full.png" alt="Screenshot of Daisy Disk with a disk nearly full" width="50%"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I've been beguiled by my local disk being almost full. This is on my
every day Mac running Tahoe 26.2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tool I turn to to debug space issues is &lt;a href="https://daisydiskapp.com/"&gt;Daisy Disk&lt;/a&gt;. It's a great tool that
I've used for years. In this case it showed the problem, but wasn't able to fix
it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not have any success through the normal means, I wrote the developer of Daisy
Disk, &lt;a href="https://daisydiskapp.com/about/"&gt;Oleg&lt;/a&gt;. They explained the problem and suggested a workaround. It worked
like a champ! I included the explanation below and screenshots showing before
and after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to say thanks to Oleg for their help! And this is a nice opportunity to
say thank you to indie developers in general who are often so helpful sharing
their expertise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oleg's explanation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
This error has recently been reported by a few other users as well, and our
investigation shows that it's caused by a new bug in macOS, introduced in one
of its recent updates. (It didn't happen before). The symptom is exactly like
in your case - a Time Machine snapshot becomes damaged for unknown reason, and
it cannot be deleted in the normal way - not only in DaisyDisk, but also not
in Terminal, using the tmutil command-line tool. Moreover, the tmutil tool
doesn't even list the damaged snapshot. It becomes almost entirely lost, while
it still consumes disk space.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We have found the following workaround solution. Please launch the system's Disk
Utility (/Applications/Utilities/Disk Utility.app) and in the left sidebar,
select your data volume, likely called "Macintosh HD - Data". Note that there
will also be another volume called "Macintosh HD" (without "Data"), but you
should select specifically "Macintosh HD - Data". Then select the View \&amp;gt; Show
APFS Snapshots menu command. In the lower part of the window, you will see the
damaged Time Machine snapshot in the list. Please select it and then click the
"-" (minus) button at the bottom to delete it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And screenshots showing the before and after. Note the two broken snapshots in
the list below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Disk utility showing disk almost full" src="https://sef.kloninger.com/f/daisy-disk-before.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Disk utility showing disk back to normal" src="https://sef.kloninger.com/f/daisy-disk-after.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Appreciation</category><category>Tech</category><guid>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/daisy-disk/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:00:21 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>