<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sef.kloninger.com (Posts about movies)</title><link>https://sef.kloninger.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://sef.kloninger.com/categories/cat_movies.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 03:53:41 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Oppenheimer -- A Miss</title><link>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/oppenheimer/</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="float:right" class="postimage" src="https://sef.kloninger.com/f/stetson.png" alt="Stetson Hat" width="40%"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was so disappointed in Oppenheimer. It wasn't terrible, but what
a missed opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mystifying&lt;/strong&gt;. Part of the job of a biopic is to give you insight
into what a person is thinking and feeling. Especially for this
movie, which is basically about this question: what would it be
like to be the person who made these terrible weapons?  I understand
he's complicated, and &lt;em&gt;it's&lt;/em&gt; complicated.  But instead of dialog,
or even some outright explaining, this movie leans on of Cillian
Murphy staring into the distance or adjusting his hat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Women&lt;/strong&gt;. There were plenty of interesting women they could have
brought in, either contemporaries, or from academia, or the
Manhattan project itself. There are only two women in the movie:
one is a sex object with mental health issues (Pugh); the other is
a mother/lush with a surprisingly sharp wit, but only for a minute
(Blunt). The sex scene, oddly using Oppenheimer's most famous line,
was gratuitous and super weird.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strauss&lt;/strong&gt;. I'm not invested at all in the conflict with &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lewis_Strauss"&gt;Admiral
Strauss&lt;/a&gt;. Paraphrasing the good folks at &lt;a href="https://www.theincomparable.com/theincomparable/703/"&gt;The Incomparable&lt;/a&gt;, "I
don't care if some guy becomes Commerce Secretary in the Eisenhower
Cabinet."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given how much I like the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Making-Atomic-Bomb-Richard-Rhodes/dp/1451677618"&gt;history and the science&lt;/a&gt; of this
period, I was really pulling for this movie. Dang.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/oppenheimer/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 21:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>