<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sef.kloninger.com (Posts about tech,warstory)</title><link>https://sef.kloninger.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://sef.kloninger.com/categories/cat_techwarstory.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 21:55:30 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Naming Is Hard</title><link>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/naming/</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lenna"&gt;&lt;img style="float:right" class="postimage" src="https://sef.kloninger.com/f/lena.png" alt="Photo of Lena Forsén" width="40%"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a story about how hard it is to come up with a good name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is in 2013 or so when I was building a &lt;a href="https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/201207on-line-education/"&gt;system online education
for Stanford&lt;/a&gt;. We started in 2012 and &lt;a href="https://engineering.stanford.edu/news/stanford-launches-class2go-open-source-platform-online-classes"&gt;launched&lt;/a&gt; a nice little
called Class2Go. The site worked well and supported the basic
features of an online course well enough: videos, assessments, auth,
reporting. We decided to keep it going and worked on it for another
year, expanding the covered use cases and taking on more classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even from the get-go the name &lt;em&gt;Class2Go&lt;/em&gt; was a bit off. The original
product was conceived as a way to take &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Massive_open_online_course"&gt;MOOC&lt;/a&gt;'s off-line. The idea
was people taking classes in poorly connected places, like low
bandwidth countries or places like your commuter train.  But the
thing we actually built didn't really support the offline use case
well anymore. In the process of getting to launch we kinda pivoted
into a more basic online-ed course system and away from the on-the-go
aspect.  It ended up being more like a little CMS backed by a
database for logins and simple assessments results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily when you're part of Stanford you have access to smart people.
We got connected to a person who does naming professionally. After
talking to us to understand the products goals and features, they
generated hundreds of candidate names. Each had gone through some
basic vetting for things like domain name availability and avoiding
potential copyright conflicts. It was my first time working with
someone like that, and they were good at it. It was a good list.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/naming/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 00:20:36 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>