<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sef.kloninger.com (Posts about Civics)</title><link>https://sef.kloninger.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://sef.kloninger.com/categories/civics.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 22:50:34 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>The Big Dig</title><link>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/big-dig/</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.wgbh.org/podcasts/the-big-dig"&gt;&lt;img style="float:right" class="postimage" src="https://sef.kloninger.com/f/bigdig.png" alt="Big Dig podcast title art (WGBH)" width="50%"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just finished the &lt;a href="https://www.wgbh.org/podcasts/the-big-dig"&gt;Big Dig podcast&lt;/a&gt; and it's worth
a listen. It's about Boston's &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_Dig"&gt;Central Artery/Tunnel Project&lt;/a&gt;,
the most expensive highway project in US history. They cover the
whole story, from conception, to getting it approved, to years of
execution, and then the fallout from cost overruns and mismanagement.
The podcast is well produced and has a lot of primary-source
interviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a little bit of a personal connection, since I lived in
Boston during the project's later years when it was on the news &lt;em&gt;all the
time&lt;/em&gt;. I even toured &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leonard_P._Zakim_Bunker_Hill_Memorial_Bridge"&gt;a part&lt;/a&gt; under construction. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what I find most compelling is trying to connect to the question,
can America build big infrastructure anymore? It's something I think
lot about. We benefit from by the giant projects from the past
(dams, bridges, interstates) but can't maintain them properly; we
struggle to take on new things like &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/California_High-Speed_Rail"&gt;high-speed rail&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They place most of the blame on headwinds that didn't exist in the
public-works heyday of the twentieth century. Leaders are under
more scrutiny; projects fall under a bunch of regulations intended
to protect the environment and workers. Public commentary slows
things down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is, while the old way was easier, it also caused a lot
of harm. I learned the story of the Cambridge and East Boston
families that stopped interstate projects that would have leveled
their homes and neighborhoods. I know those places well. I used to
own a home right where &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interstate_695_(Massachusetts)"&gt;one of those roads was supposed to have
been&lt;/a&gt;. I sure am grateful to those protesters who won!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It ends on a hopeful note. Not that it's easy, nor are we necessarily
that much better managing big projects now. But there are success
stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One part I especially liked was &lt;a href="https://overcast.fm/+BDdBHAXcVU/20:47"&gt;20 minutes into the final episode&lt;/a&gt;,
in the final interview with &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frederick_P._Salvucci"&gt;Fred Salvucci&lt;/a&gt;, where he told the
story Saint Francis. God tells Francis to build a cathedral, but
then tears it down. Francis builds another, God destroys it again.
Why, Francis asks. Because it's not enough to build a physical
cathedral, but you also have to build the support for it in the
hearts and minds of the people. Maybe that's the part we're not
doing well enough now.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Civics</category><category>Media</category><guid>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/big-dig/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>