<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sef.kloninger.com (Posts about Data)</title><link>https://sef.kloninger.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://sef.kloninger.com/categories/data.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 19:25:28 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Learn From Experiments</title><link>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/experiments/</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="float:right" class="postimage" src="https://sef.kloninger.com/f/experiment.jpeg" alt="Line art of an experiment" width="60%"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What's the value of an experiment or a prototype?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are all kinds of ways to have impact. A feature can improve user
experience; a hardening project can reduce risk of a production outage;
refactoring or test coverage can improve velocity or make software easier and
safer to maintain. And good engineers care a lot about impact. While it's not
the only thing that matters (the "how" is important too), if you start with
impact, you'll generally do well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An engineer's job to put ideas into practice, to make things. But sometimes
we're not sure what to make. Or we think we know, but aren't sure it'll work.
The best way to figure that out is often running a set of experiments, or maybe
building a prototype (an n=1 experiment).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But crucially, an experiment doesn't have value itself. An experiment is
successful only if we've learned something. The intent of the test rig or
prototype isn't to live on. Indeed, knowing that we plan to throw it away is
part of what makes it fast and cheap to build, and it shouldn't have all the
trappings of production-quality software, like test coverage and code reviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how do we ensure that value gets delivered? When you work in a team or a
company people turn over. It's not just enough to do the experiment, you need to
write it up and share your results. To produce a good writeup, you should:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure out the hypothesis(es)&lt;/strong&gt; you're testing. Often this is in the form
   of one or more questions. For prototypes, it might be a boolean, i.e. we can
   build X that will work. But even then, consider what "done" means. Stating
   your hypothesis in terms of a metric is often easiest. NB I find the
   goal/driver/guardrail framework from Thanks &lt;a href="https://research.google/people/author3770/?&amp;amp;type=google"&gt;Diane&lt;/a&gt;'s book helpful,
   &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/books/edition/Trustworthy_Online_Controlled_Experiment/TFjPDwAAQBAJ?hl=en&amp;amp;gbpv=1"&gt;Trustworthy Online Controlled Experiments&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;State your assumptions and method&lt;/strong&gt;. This is where you usually get the most
   feedback. Note that this usually isn't a project plan, as your reviewers
   usually don't care how long it takes or what happens when. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seek feedback&lt;/strong&gt; from your peers. Publish the doc stating the method to have
   smart people poke holes in your plan and make sure what you're measuring will
   actually address the hypothesis. And then when the experiment is done, get it
   reviewed by someone senior to ensure that your work supports your conclusion.
   This also spreads knowledge about this work (both that you're doing it, and
   the results) so the overall organization benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The artifact produced has many benefits. It's useful for you as you discuss
follow-on work; it's useful come performance evaluation time. But most
importantly, it benefits the organization. Contemporary and future peers can
learn from this work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll benefit from taking the time to write it up, the reviewers learn from
reading, and it'll live on past your time with the team.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Data</category><category>Engineering</category><category>Management</category><guid>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/experiments/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Flat</title><link>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/halloween-2015/</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Trick-or-treaters volume at our Menlo Park house this Halloween was basically flat compared to last
year. Last year we had 208 trick-or-treaters, this year 211. We remain down quite a bit from our 2012
peak. Maybe this is the new norm?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="400" frameborder="0" src="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1w-7ftYzue_VQl4lt-QNFU_UfeDAROg47-1tlOzIw5Vk/pubchart?oid=17&amp;amp;format=interactive"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything happened later this year. Our first trick-or-treater didn't show up until 6:30, and
peak wasn't until 8:45. That's thirty minutes or more later than prior years. I speculate it's because
it was a warm weekend night. Why not stay out a bit later, no school tomorrow. And with the fall-back
DST change everyone would be looking foward to a "free" hour of sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, the full story can be seen 
&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/ccc?key=0AnpKmkglpRs5dDh3dWRmRlFVaG0yc08xU0lhTzF1NUE"&gt;
in the numbers&lt;/a&gt;. Check it out!&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Data</category><guid>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/halloween-2015/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 08:15:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fewer Trick or Treaters This Year</title><link>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/halloween-2014/</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;This year's Halloween tally was 208.  I don't know why we have 32%
fewer trick-or-treaters than we had last year, which was down 20%
from the year before that.  Maybe the rain earlier in the day kept
people home.  Maybe because it was Friday people opted for parties
instead of going door to door.  I don't know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script type="text/javascript" src="//ajax.googleapis.com/ajax/static/modules/gviz/1.0/chart.js"&gt;
{"dataSourceUrl":"//docs.google.com/spreadsheet/tq?key=0AnpKmkglpRs5dDh3dWRmRlFVaG0yc08xU0lhTzF1NUE&amp;transpose=1&amp;headers=0&amp;range=C20%3AH21&amp;gid=9&amp;pub=1","options":{"titleTextStyle":{"bold":true,"color":"#000","fontSize":"24"},"series":{"0":{"color":"#b45f06"}},"animation":{"duration":500},"width":600,"hAxis":{"useFormatFromData":true,"title":"","minValue":null,"viewWindowMode":null,"textStyle":{"bold":true,"color":"#222","fontSize":"20"},"viewWindow":null,"maxValue":null},"vAxes":[{"useFormatFromData":true,"title":"","minValue":0,"viewWindowMode":"explicit","textStyle":{"bold":true,"color":"#222","fontSize":"20"},"logScale":false,"viewWindow":{"min":0,"max":null},"maxValue":null},{"useFormatFromData":true,"minValue":null,"logScale":false,"viewWindow":{"min":null,"max":null},"maxValue":null}],"booleanRole":"certainty","title":"Trick or Treaters, Menlo Park, CA","height":240,"legend":"none","useFirstColumnAsDomain":true,"isStacked":false,"tooltip":{}},"state":{},"view":{},"isDefaultVisualization":false,"chartType":"ColumnChart","chartName":"Chart 4"}
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to my friend Stuart for being on this year's data gathering
crew.  As usual, the full story is 
&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/ccc?key=0AnpKmkglpRs5dDh3dWRmRlFVaG0yc08xU0lhTzF1NUE"&gt;in the numbers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Data</category><guid>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/halloween-2014/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 09:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>In Praise of the Hand Tally</title><link>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/hand-tally/</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="float:right" class="postimage" src="https://sef.kloninger.com/f/tallies.jpg" alt="Tally Marks" width="height=174"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past five years I've gathered statistics on how many
trick-or-treaters have come by on Halloween.  If you want to read
about that, check out posts from &lt;a href="https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/201311halloween-2013.html"&gt;last year&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/201210halloween-candy-data.html"&gt;the year before&lt;/a&gt;.
This post is about &lt;strong&gt;how&lt;/strong&gt; I track those stats, and how I don't.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every year I'm tempted to build some fancy system to collect and
manage these statistics.  Wouldn't it be fun, say, to wire up some
Raspberry Pi sensor that automatically counts and tweets running
totals?  It wouldn't be &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; hard and sounds like fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is making something like that reliable.  You'd have to
do all the un-fun stuff, like testing and contingency planning.  If
your baseline is a clipboard, paper, and a ball point pen, your bar
for failure is basically "never".  Even if I did build something
fancy I'd still end up doing backup tallies by hand.  At this human
scale, the tech ends up being a fun gimmick, not required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It reminds me of a story from friend [Tony].  Tony
and his brother &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ProtomCannon"&gt;Tom&lt;/a&gt; run a giant gaming convention every year,
the &lt;a href="http://evo.shoryuken.com/"&gt;Evolution Championship Series&lt;/a&gt; (Evo for short).  It's a
multi-day convention in Las Vegas that attracts something like ten
thousand participants.  They run the whole thing with their two
other founders and some friends — I'm sure they have some
paid help now, but the four guys are the main ones.  It's impressive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="center"&gt;
&lt;img src="http://evo.shoryuken.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/9450177474_3d2e293e9d_b.jpg" style="padding-top:20px; padding-bottom:20px"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that Tony and Tom are strong engineers, I figured this would
be a slick high-tech operation.  Not so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tony said they've tried tech at various points and it wasn't worth
it.  It's easy to see why that is tempting: they have multiple
mobile coordinators that need access to changing, shared information,
like brackets and schedules.  But what they've tried has let them
down.  Usually it's not the hard parts that fail, but the basics,
like batteries and wireless connectivity.  So they still run this
off of printouts and voice communications (cell phones/walkie-talkies)
and periodic data dumps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so, this year I'll be gathering my Halloween stats like I always
have: clipboard, pen, and a hand-held &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/STEELMASTER-Counter-Inches-Silver-200100492/dp/B0089KJSFQ/ref=sr_1_3"&gt;tally counter&lt;/a&gt;.  The data
will still be timely and accurate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the curious few, check out my &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/ccc?key=0AnpKmkglpRs5dDh3dWRmRlFVaG0yc08xU0lhTzF1NUE"&gt;Halloween Traffic Spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two postscripts.  First, Please stop spreading that
&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LQy1DH38E5g"&gt;NASA Space Pen story&lt;/a&gt;.  I'm sure you've heard it: how do you write in zero G?
the wasteful Americans commissioned a multi-million dollar space
pen project; the scrappy can-do Russians used pencils.  Well, this
story has been &lt;a href="http://www.snopes.com/business/genius/spacepen.asp"&gt;debunked by the good people at Snopes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And second, I'd like to plug Tony and Tom's "day job", &lt;a href="http://stonehearth.net/"&gt;Stonehearth&lt;/a&gt;.
I think of it as Starcraft meets Minecraft.  I am so eager to play
it when it lands.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Data</category><guid>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/hand-tally/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2014 16:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Halloween Down 20%, But Still Solid</title><link>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/halloween-2013/</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignright  wp-image-440" style="border: 0px;" alt="halloween2013-ticker" src="https://sef.kloninger.com/f/halloween2013-ticker-300x300.jpg" width="126" height="126"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
This year we had a sizable number of trick-or-treaters at our house in the Willows neighborhood of Menlo Park. The 303 we saw was down from our high last year, but abou the same as the year before that.



&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So here are the totals:



&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="center"&gt;
&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-441 alignnone" style="border: 0px;" alt="halloween2013-total" src="https://sef.kloninger.com/f/halloween2013-total-300x184.png" width="300" height="184"&gt;



&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The rate at peak was comparable to last year.


&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="row-fluid"&gt;
&lt;div class="span2" align="center"&gt;
&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-443 alignnone" style="border: 0px;" alt="halloween2013-rate" src="https://sef.kloninger.com/f/halloween2013-rate-300x160.png" width="300" height="160"&gt; 
       
&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-442 alignnone" style="border: 0px;" alt="halloween2013-cumulative" src="https://sef.kloninger.com/f/halloween2013-cumulative-300x158.png" width="300" height="158"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
I don't have an explanation why we are down a bit. The weather was beautiful, indeed a little better than last year since rain started at 8:30 last year. Maybe the forecast rain coming last year got people out earlier who might have missed altogether?



&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It was outstanding having my friend &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/amylameyer"&gt;Amy LaMeyer&lt;/a&gt; helping out. She operated the clicker that was new this year, and so kept me company, which was a ton of fun.



&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
As always, the Google Spreadsheet with the graphs and raw data is publicly available &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/ccc?key=0AnpKmkglpRs5dDh3dWRmRlFVaG0yc08xU0lhTzF1NUE"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Check it out!&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Data</category><guid>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/halloween-2013/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2013 05:25:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Halloween Candy Data</title><link>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/halloween-candy-data/</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Update with actuals from Halloween 2012:  It was a banner year.


&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="center"&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-391" alt="halloween-2012" src="https://sef.kloninger.com/f/halloween-2012-1024x433.png" width="584" height="246"&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
You may be giving out candy later today. What can you expect? Let's look at some data.  This post summarizes the past three Halloweens.



&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="center"&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone  wp-image-378" style="border: 0px;" title="cumulative" alt="Cumulative Trick or Treaters" src="https://sef.kloninger.com/f/cumulative-1024x441.png" width="584" height="251"&gt;



&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
As you can see we live in a pretty popular neighborhood.  Each year has its own story.

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt; - our first year in our new neighborhood. We had no idea that this was such a popular trick-or-treating spot. I ran out of candy at 8:00, turned out the lights, and hid in the back of the house. Shameful.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt; - a fine year.  No complaints.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2011&lt;/strong&gt; - we moved to a new house just around the corner.  I figured the quieter street would mean fewer kids -- not so! What I didn't appreciate was the attractive power of my next door neighbor's &lt;em&gt;insane&lt;/em&gt; decorations. Luckily my wife came back with emergency supplies just in time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
And how busy do things get?  Darn busy.



&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="center"&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone  wp-image-379" style="border: 0px;" title="rates" alt="Average and Max Trick or Treaters per Minute" src="https://sef.kloninger.com/f/rates-1024x412.png" width="584" height="234"&gt;



&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
During the busiest 15 minute period last year I was serving a kid every twenty seconds or so.  When bursting this is close to my max current candy-dispensing throughput.



&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If you come by my house this year you'll see me again, handing out candy with one hand and scribbling hash marks with the other.   I'll update the data in my &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/ccc?key=0AnpKmkglpRs5dDh3dWRmRlFVaG0yc08xU0lhTzF1NUE"&gt;public spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Data</category><category>Life</category><guid>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/halloween-candy-data/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 07:19:35 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>