<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sef.kloninger.com (Posts about Life)</title><link>https://sef.kloninger.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://sef.kloninger.com/categories/life.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:38:23 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Data Is Worth Preserving</title><link>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/data-preservation/</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="float:right" class="postimage" src="https://sef.kloninger.com/f/drp-logo.jpg" alt="Logo for the Data Rescue Project" width="30%"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Governments should produce &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Public_good"&gt;public goods&lt;/a&gt;, like navigation aids and roads. That
seems like a reasonable thing to expect of a functioning government, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I consider data a public good too. We all benefit from accurate maps,
thorough measurements of the natural world, and trustworthy economic data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which is why it was I was so upset when I heard how the the current US
administration has been on a tear to &lt;strong&gt;actually remove data&lt;/strong&gt;. All through 2025,
websites were taking down and datasets were taken offline. This &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2025_United_States_government_online_resource_removals"&gt;Wikipedia page&lt;/a&gt;
catalogs what's been happening, and this report by the &lt;a href="https://www.amstat.org/policy-and-advocacy/the-nation's-data-at-risk-meeting-american's-information-needs-for-the-21st-century"&gt;American Statistical
Association&lt;/a&gt; goes into more depth about what's been happening and its
implications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response the &lt;a href="https://www.datarescueproject.org/"&gt;Data Rescue Project&lt;/a&gt; sprang into action. They're a group of
concerned academics, librarians, and citizens who have been copying and
cataloging datasets so they aren't lost. The &lt;a href="https://www.datarescueproject.org/press/"&gt;project's press page&lt;/a&gt; has links to
many articles and presentations that describe their work and its impact. Last
November I saw a call for volunteers for DRP on a mailing list of ex-Googlers
and was eager to help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Homeland Infrastructure Foundation-Level Data (HIFLD)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's worth describing a bit about the particular dataset I actually worked on:
Homeland Infrastructure Foundation-Level Data (HIFLD). It's a good case study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HIFLD is a collection of maps. Maps of basic stuff, like roads, levees, river
depth charts, locations of military bases. Beyond just being good maps, a big
part of HIFLD's value is helping to make sure everyone uses &lt;em&gt;the same maps&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So HIFLD is mostly curating data. Most of the data comes from other agencies
(USGS, Army Corps of Engineers, Census Bureau) and HIFLD brings it together and
provides it in a trustworthy, central place. Well, I should say "provided"
because in September the &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/gis/comments/1lkol3s/sad_news_hifld_open_to_be_discontinued_by_sept_30/"&gt;government stopped providing it&lt;/a&gt;. The story is well
told in this good &lt;a href="https://projectgeospatial.org/geospatial-frontiers/the-rise-power-and-uncertain-future-of-americas-open-infrastructure-data"&gt;article on Project Geospatial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where the Data Rescue Project comes in. DRP volunteers immediately
scooped up the data and kept in temporary storage. Then they organized a bucket
brigade of volunteers to categorize and put &lt;a href="https://www.datalumos.org/datalumos/search/studies?q=hifld%20open"&gt;snapshots&lt;/a&gt; into long-term storage.
Importantly, this was coupled with metadata to ensure they're findable later.
That's the part I worked on, uploading and entering metadata. We met our goal of
getting all of HIFLD "rescued" by year's end. &lt;a href="https://libguides.brown.edu/prf.php?account_id=276524"&gt;Frank Donnelly&lt;/a&gt;, the project
manager, wrote up a nice &lt;a href="https://www.datarescueproject.org/hifld-data-saved/"&gt;summary&lt;/a&gt; of what we did and how. For my piece I relied
on a nice Selenium driver, written by another volunteer, to create over a
hundred projects (&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/dVadwqbJoSs"&gt;screen recording&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just one of many DRP efforts. Check out their &lt;a href="https://www.datarescueproject.org/data-rescue-tracker/"&gt;tracker&lt;/a&gt; to see the
breadth of work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I'm proud of this project, I keep reminding myself that we're playing
defense. Having a one-time snapshot isn't nearly as good as having the
government actually do its job. Which is why we need to keep demanding better
leadership and a return to effective government. Assert your rights and
&lt;a href="https://www.nokings.org/"&gt;protest&lt;/a&gt;!   ❌ 👑.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Civics</category><category>Life</category><category>Tech</category><guid>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/data-preservation/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Rob Reiner: "Whatever you like to do, do a lot of it. Do it every day."</title><link>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/rob-reiner/</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="float:right" class="postimage" src="https://sef.kloninger.com/f/rob-reiner.jpg" alt="Photo of Rob Reiner from Wikipedia, source Neil Grabowsky / Montclair Film Festival" width="30%"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was fortunate to have met and shared a meal with Rob Reiner some years back. I
wanted to take a moment to share this story on the sad occasion of his death
this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was 2003 or so. I lived and worked for Akamai in Boston. I had been going
back and forth to San Mateo office a fair bit that year, often taking a red eye
home from San Jose. Back then the San Jose airport was smaller than it is now,
and was especially quiet at the evenings. Not a lot of dinner options, so
McDonald's it was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That day I was surprised to recognize Rob Reiner in line right in front of me!
He was traveling with some assistant-type person, patiently waiting. I tend to
not bother celebrities in public, but I was moved to say something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sef&lt;/strong&gt;: Hello Mr. Reiner. Forgive me but I just wanted to say how much I enjoy
your work. I'm a really big fan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rob Reiner&lt;/strong&gt; (big grin): Hi! What's your name? Thanks for introducing
yourself. What have I done that you like?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think he genuinely wanted to know. I knew his big films pretty well —
&lt;em&gt;When Harry Met Sally&lt;/em&gt; was the most popular, &lt;em&gt;A Few Good Men&lt;/em&gt; had been up for
Best Picture, &lt;em&gt;Spinal Tap&lt;/em&gt; is well, Spinal Tap. These are all really great
films.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sef&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;The Princess Bride&lt;/em&gt;, hands down. I love the story and I love what you
did with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rob Reiner&lt;/strong&gt;: I'm glad you said that. That's my favorite too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hearing that was more than I'd hoped for. I thanked him and begged off so he
could order his burger and have dinner in peace. But no, in that New Yorker
voice and with a big smile he said, "C'mon, let's have cheeseburgers!" The three
of us all sat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a nice talk over dinner. He asked questions and seemed genuinely
interested in what I did -- work, family. But the highlight was toward the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rob Reiner&lt;/strong&gt;: What else can I answer for you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sef&lt;/strong&gt;: What would you tell someone early in their career?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point I was about thirty years old, so hardly &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; early in my own
career, but I was asking in a genuine way. He answered straight away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rob Reiner&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;mark&gt;Whatever you like to do, do a lot of it. Do it every
day.&lt;/mark&gt; Me, I like writing so I try to do that of it every day if I can.
That's how you get good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He then told a few stories about people he'd met who don't do this. I guess when
you're someone like him, people ask you frequently for jobs or if you'd produce
their movie or whatnot. He said he asks what was the last thing they'd written,
or what they were working on now, or what'd they'd written today. And he could
tell if they did it often and did it for fun. If they didn't do it often, then
how good a writer were they likely to be?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was struck by what a nice and interesting, and interested, person Rob Reiner
was. It was incredibly generous for him to spend time with a fanboy when he
could be off duty and just enjoying his cheeseburger. What a gem.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Appreciation</category><category>Life</category><category>Media</category><guid>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/rob-reiner/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Three Months</title><link>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/three-months/</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I've been &lt;a href="https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/leaving-google"&gt;off work&lt;/a&gt; for about three months now. It's a
good occasion to take stock of how that's going. In a word, it's been &lt;strong&gt;great&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="float:right" class="postimage" src="https://sef.kloninger.com/f/activities.jpeg" alt="Meme from the movie \" step brothers\" showing men playing in a bedroom with the caption \"we have so much room for activities.\"" width="50%"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm surprised how much lighter my mood is. It feels like a weight that I've
  been carrying around for some time is no longer there. It's different than
  being on vacation, better actually. I didn't appreciate how stressful
  tech management has been all these years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm taking a ton of pleasure in simple things. I go grocery shopping almost
  every day, I'm doing a ton of cooking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels good to get healthier. I had knee surgery and am recovering from that
  just fine. I exercise nearly every day. On days that I don't go to &lt;a href="https://www.bayclubs.com/clubs/redwoodshores"&gt;the
  gym&lt;/a&gt; I do thirty minutes on the bike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's great to have flexibility. I hadn't planned to see my Dad on his 80th
  birthday because we'd on a bigger group thing later. But on a whim I drove
  down and took him out for breakfast on his actual birthday, because why not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I didn't want to do it before, I still don't want to do it. The closet
  hasn't gotten cleaned out; neither has the garage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My friend Rachel Grey has a three month head start leaving Google. Her
writing this resonates with me. Especially this from recent LinkedIn post
(&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/rachel-grey-b69319_after-six-months-out-of-tech-my-primary-ugcPost-7383907826374582272-yCCs"&gt;private, sorry&lt;/a&gt;): "one month off per year of service is a good rule of
thumb; after six of them, I'm still feeling like a sailor who just barely
managed to swim to shore." Maybe that's still where I'm at too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what have I been doing?  I'm prioritizing friends and family — I'm
lucky to have a lot of people I care about. I'm embarrassed that I haven't
always been good about staying in touch, but I can fix that now. And fun stuff
like &lt;a href="https://planet-bridge.org/index.php"&gt;bridge lessons&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond that, I'm getting involved with a couple of small projects but nothing
serious yet. When I find something interesting, I'll write about it here.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Life</category><guid>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/three-months/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Leaving Google</title><link>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/leaving-google/</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="float:right" class="postimage" src="https://sef.kloninger.com/f/google-10year.jpeg" alt="Sef holding a framed certificate, Google ten years of service." width="60%"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An offer of a Voluntary Exit from Google HR landed in my mailbox right around my
ten-year anniversary with the company, give or take. We'd had a couple of
packages like this at Google before (&lt;a href="https://9to5google.com/2025/01/30/pixel-android-voluntary-exit-employees/"&gt;news&lt;/a&gt;), basically the same deal you'd
get if you got laid off. But this was the first one put in front of those of us
working in one of the revenue engines of the company — I worked on Search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wasn't aiming to leave. I liked the work, I had a good team and boss. But
the package was enough to kickstart a discussion, "why &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; now?". My wife and
I ran numbers and discussed our futures. I clicked the button. My last day as a
Googler was earlier this week, October 4th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have good feelings about my time at Google. It was nice that I saw a some
different parts of the business: some consumer (three years at YouTube, four
years at Search) and some enterprise (three years at Cloud). I got to play with
big infrastructure and solve some hard problems. I saw behind the curtain. But
the best part was the smart and interesting people I got to work with. I know
it's a cliche, but it's the truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not everything was great. I've decided to not use this space for dishy stories
about how Google isn't all it claims to be. But I sure do love reminiscing and
grousing as much as any engineer. If you want to share war stories over a beer,
I'm always up for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's next? I haven't decided if this is retirement, or a sabbatical, or
something else. I've been off work for extended stretches twice before, once by
choice and once not. Those two times taught me that the difference between a
wonderful, mind-expanding time and a stress-fest is my own mindset. And now
that I haven't been really working for six weeks now, I can confidently say
that my mindset is positive and good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm excited about the next phase. I feel fortunate to have some time to focus on
what's important.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Life</category><category>Technology</category><guid>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/leaving-google/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Working In The Open</title><link>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/working-in-the-open/</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="float:right" class="postimage" src="https://sef.kloninger.com/f/hachyderm-debugging.png" alt="screenshot of @nova live-debugging Hachyderm on Twitch" width="50%"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other day my daughter asked me about Software Engineering -- what do
we &lt;em&gt;actually do&lt;/em&gt;? She's eighteen and probably won't follow in my
footsteps, which is fine, but I still want her to see my field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've always found this question hard to answer. I've been an engineering
manager for a long time, and I'm happy to describe that job (emails,
1:1's, PRD reviews), but I don't think that's the heart of it. Plus
these days I work for Google where things there are proprietary and
deeply layered, not much help for answering questions like these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I've found my way to Mastodon for &lt;a href="https://hachyderm.io/@sefk/109456480817920873"&gt;obvious reasons&lt;/a&gt;. I
chose the &lt;a href="https://hachyderm.io/"&gt;Hachyderm&lt;/a&gt; instance because it was well run by people who
shared my values. It turns out that the values of the owners and
operators of the things we use matter, huh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then learned a cool thing, that the Hachyderm admins do much of their
work publicly. They livestream debugging sessions on &lt;a href="https://www.twitch.tv/krisnova"&gt;Twitch&lt;/a&gt;, they write
postmortems, they share live &lt;a href="https://grafana.hachyderm.io/public-dashboards/445bbb0e169f4e86b1d1eeee7e50c92a"&gt;graphs&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://hachyderm.io/@nova"&gt;@nova&lt;/a&gt; happened to be
live-streaming at that moment, not surprising since the team's been busy
absorbing thousands of new users and fending off attacks. My daughter
and I watched a bit together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Hachyderm (&lt;a href="https://hachyderm.io/@nova"&gt;@nova&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://hachyderm.io/@dma"&gt;@dma&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://hachyderm.io/@quintessence"&gt;@quintessence&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://hachyderm.io/@Taniwha"&gt;@Taniwha&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https://hachyderm.io/@hazelweakly"&gt;@hazelweakly&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://hachyderm.io/@malte"&gt;@malte&lt;/a&gt;): thank you for running this service well.
But also thank you for giving me something I'm proud to use and proud to
show my kid.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Life</category><guid>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/working-in-the-open/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 17:47:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>YouTube</title><link>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/youtube/</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="float:right" class="postimage" src="https://sef.kloninger.com/f/YouTube-icon-full_color.png" alt="YouTube" width="200px" height="148px"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm excited to start my new job at YouTube in a few weeks. I'll manage the
engineering team building the data warehouse for usage metrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like that YouTube is &lt;strong&gt;important&lt;/strong&gt;. It's firmly a part of our culture
and I'm sure it will be how my kids watch video. YouTube's impressive
&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/yt/press/statistics.html"&gt;statistics&lt;/a&gt; are the result. You don't see usage like that without a
bunch of &lt;strong&gt;hard problems&lt;/strong&gt;, and hard problems attract &lt;strong&gt;bright people&lt;/strong&gt;.
Indeed that's the clincher for why I'm looking forward to working there.
People vote with their feet, and I have a lot of friends who have opted
for Google, and YouTube specifically. They tell me that it's a great place
to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YouTube is one of the worlds foremost platforms for social commentary,
education, and free speech. And it's plenty of &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9bZkp7q19f0"&gt;entertainment&lt;/a&gt; too. Sounds
like fun.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Life</category><category>Technology</category><guid>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/youtube/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2015 06:25:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>My Next Job</title><link>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/job-15/</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="float:right" class="postimage" src="https://sef.kloninger.com/f/snowflake.png" alt="Snowflake" width="25%"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I left &lt;a href="http://www.wavefront.com/"&gt;my last job&lt;/a&gt; a few weeks back and it's high time to look for a new
one. If you're working on something interesting and think I could help, &lt;a href="mailto:sefklon@gmail.com"&gt;let
me know&lt;/a&gt;! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's nice to not have a day job while looking for another. I was lucky enough
to do this &lt;a href="https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/201204my-sabbatical.html"&gt;once before in 2012&lt;/a&gt; which turned out great. I learned then
that time and flexibility lets you talk to lots of friends and learn about a
breadth of projects. I found a fun project in a new domain (&lt;a href="https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/201207on-line-education.html"&gt;online
education&lt;/a&gt;), something I doubt I'd have found the normal way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe I'll get lucky again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enough small talk, what am I looking for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm looking for some flavor of &lt;strong&gt;line manager&lt;/strong&gt;. I'm a good senior manager and
code-every-day engineer; but I'm exceptional leading a team and running a
project. That's what line managers do: lead engineers, not other managers or
departments or matrix-anything. Also, if you're some kind of executive then
coding is an indulgence, and I'd rather it just be part of my job. Mostly I'm
talking to &lt;strong&gt;small companies&lt;/strong&gt;, say 10-100 people (fun-size).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to &lt;strong&gt;build on my experience&lt;/strong&gt;. I know infrastructure and cloud, SaaS
and enterprise, and online education. I'm probably not the best person for
your storage, security, gaming, e-commerce, or cryptocurrency company. I want
to stay working on &lt;strong&gt;Internet technology&lt;/strong&gt;. I like the (micro)services model.
For my own projects I choose Python, JavaScript (frontend and backend), and
Java. I know web operations, especially the &lt;a href="https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/aws.html"&gt;Amazon stack&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt; is important: I don't want to do a daily Menlo Park to San
Francisco round-trip. I'd like to &lt;strong&gt;work with friends&lt;/strong&gt; if possible. And I
want to do something &lt;strong&gt;worthwhile&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can always get to my resume from the header here, or via this &lt;a href="http://bit.ly/sef-resume"&gt;short
link&lt;/a&gt;. I'm open to a bunch of things, just no &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VEgu7jdc_fs"&gt;kick boxing&lt;/a&gt;.  Let's
have coffee/drink or take a walk.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Life</category><category>Technology</category><guid>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/job-15/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2015 16:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Perspective</title><link>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/petrol-car/</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;div style="float:right; padding-left:15px;"&gt;
    &lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"&gt;
        &lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Test drive of a petrol car - &lt;a href="http://t.co/lPQ0xcs7uU"&gt;http://t.co/lPQ0xcs7uU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— sefk (@sefk) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sefk/status/595318498894553088"&gt;May 4, 2015&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right when I was thinking about writing a post about much we overlook
the sins of the status quo, some Swedes
&lt;a href="http://teslaclubsweden.se/test-drive-of-a-petrol-car/"&gt;took care of it for me&lt;/a&gt;. Tack vänner!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tear around town carrying gallons of incendiary liquid just inches
beneath my beloved family? 
In a mode of transport that &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_motor_vehicle_deaths_in_U.S._by_year"&gt;kills upwards of thirty thousand Americans every year&lt;/a&gt;? 
Sure, that's fine.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Life</category><guid>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/petrol-car/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 07:05:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Don't Say No By Email</title><link>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/saying-no/</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="float:right" class="postimage" src="https://sef.kloninger.com/f/frown.png" alt=":(" width="192" height="178"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I have to tell someone no, I pick up the phone. I &lt;strong&gt;hate&lt;/strong&gt;
talking on the phone, but I do it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you're answering no to someone, you're disappointing them even
if just a little bit. So you owe it to them to talk instead of
sending an email. It's the polite thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there are two other reasons, selfish reasons, for making the
call. First, you get immediate feedback on how they took the news.
If they're upset then you can do damage control straight away. And
at least you know! And second, delivering bad news directly and
respectfully is an important skill to develop. We can all use the
practice. And it's never as bad as I think it will be.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Life</category><guid>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/saying-no/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2015 01:08:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Arthroscopy Is Amazing</title><link>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/arthroscopy/</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="float:right" class="postimage" src="https://sef.kloninger.com/f/sef-left-knee.png" alt="My Left Knee" width="30%"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three days ago I was hobbling around on a sore knee with a torn
meniscus. But after just three days of icing and Ibuprofen and
resting on the couch already my knee is almost better than it was
before. This arthroscopic surgery stuff is amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My knee had been getting progressively worse for the past few months.
But the clincher was six weeks ago, when I was chasing around a dog that
was loose in our front yard. A twist, pop, and I was down. The doctor
I saw the next day confirmed that it wasn't anything "serious" like a
torn ligament, but something was definitely wrong. When we went up to
a week of family camping a few weeks back, I couldn't go on any hikes
and could barely play ping pong. It was a real bummer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I met with a sports medicine doctor at Palo Alto Medical Foundation
and got an MRI. He saw a few things wrong in there. A few days later, I
was getting the procedure done. Viola. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterwards I was surprised that it didn't hurt. They did prescribe
some pain medication (Hydrocodone plus Acetaminophen) that I've
been taking when I go to bed, but haven't needed during the day.
I've been using a &lt;a href="http://www.djoglobal.com/products/donjoy/donjoy-iceman-clear3"&gt;machine that pumps ice water through a pad&lt;/a&gt;
around my knee all day to keep it cool, and that's worked really
well. &lt;strong&gt;So much better&lt;/strong&gt; than ice packs. Totally recommend the ice
machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the good surgical team at &lt;a href="http://www.pamf.org/sports/"&gt;Palo Alto Medical Foundation&lt;/a&gt;
especially &lt;a href="https://www.sutterhealth.org/find-provider/dr-colin-l-eakin-1046233844"&gt;Dr. Colin Eakin&lt;/a&gt;. Their surgery center on Willow Road
made the whole experience smooth and reassuring. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But one pro tip for you out there considering this. Don't read the
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/General_anaesthesia"&gt;wikipedia article on General Anesthesia&lt;/a&gt; the night before
surgery. It's crazy stuff. Especially the parts about how we're
still not really sure how it works, or the part about how the level
of anesthesia where it is safe to operate is right between "excitement"
where you vomit and twitch, and "overdose" where you stop breathing.
Don't read that part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm back to work tomorrow, and I expect to be back on my bike by next
week!&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Life</category><guid>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/arthroscopy/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 05:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>