<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>sef.kloninger.com (Life)</title><link>http://sef.kloninger.com/</link><description></description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 12:08:31 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>http://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Arthroscopy Is Amazing</title><link>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/arthroscopy.html</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="float:right" class="postimage" src="http://sef.kloninger.com/f/sef-left-knee.png" alt="My Left Knee" width="30%"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three days ago I was hobbling around on a sore knee with a torn
meniscus. But after just three days of icing and Ibuprofen and
resting on the couch already my knee is almost better than it was
before. This arthroscopic surgery stuff is amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My knee had been getting progressively worse for the past few months.
But the clincher was six weeks ago, when I was chasing around a dog that
was loose in our front yard. A twist, pop, and I was down. The doctor
I saw the next day confirmed that it wasn't anything "serious" like a
torn ligament, but something was definitely wrong. When we went up to
a week of family camping a few weeks back, I couldn't go on any hikes
and could barely play ping pong. It was a real bummer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I met with a sports medicine doctor at Palo Alto Medical Foundation
and got an MRI. He saw a few things wrong in there. A few days later, I
was getting the procedure done. Viola. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterwards I was surprised that it didn't hurt. They did prescribe
some pain medication (Hydrocodone plus Acetaminophen) that I've
been taking when I go to bed, but haven't needed during the day.
I've been using a &lt;a href="http://www.djoglobal.com/products/donjoy/donjoy-iceman-clear3"&gt;machine that pumps ice water through a pad&lt;/a&gt;
around my knee all day to keep it cool, and that's worked really
well. &lt;strong&gt;So much better&lt;/strong&gt; than ice packs. Totally recommend the ice
machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the good surgical team at &lt;a href="http://www.pamf.org/sports/"&gt;Palo Alto Medical Foundation&lt;/a&gt;
especially &lt;a href="http://www.pamf.org/dr-colin-l-eakin.html"&gt;Dr. Colin Eakin&lt;/a&gt;. Their surgery center on Willow Road
made the whole experience smooth and reassuring. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But one pro tip for you out there considering this. Don't read the
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/General_anaesthesia"&gt;wikipedia article on General Anesthesia&lt;/a&gt; the night before
surgery. It's crazy stuff. Especially the parts about how we're
still not really sure how it works, or the part about how the level
of anesthesia where it is safe to operate is right between "excitement"
where you vomit and twitch, and "overdose" where you stop breathing.
Don't read that part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm back to work tomorrow, and I expect to be back on my bike by next
week!&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Life</category><guid>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/arthroscopy.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 05:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>David Bowie To The Rescue</title><link>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/earworm.html</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;p style="float:right; align:right; width:30%"&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Bowie_JohnDancing1.jpg#mediaviewer/File:Bowie_JohnDancing1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="postimage" src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/b/bb/Bowie_JohnDancing1.jpg" alt="Bowie JohnDancing1.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often wake up with a song going through my head. I don't know
why this happens. The stranger thing the songs. Yesterday
was good, I woke up to Led Zepplin's &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JjlJBmwF3PI"&gt;Immigrant Song&lt;/a&gt; —
what a great way to start the day. But earlier in the week it was
inexplicably the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KiQzUEc_FmI"&gt;Golden Girls Theme Song&lt;/a&gt;. Gah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've heard them called earworms: songs that get stuck in your head and
don't get out. So I'll share with you now the antidote, taught to
me by my good friend &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jinpa1345"&gt;Jane Manning&lt;/a&gt;.  Thanks, Jane!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sing David Bowie's song &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6VrqCBsbeuc"&gt;John, I'm Only Dancing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;
Not one of Bowie's better known songs, nor even one of his best, but
remarkably well suited to this. I believe it's because the
melody is kind of odd and not all that pleasant, so it's not going
to get stuck itself. You kind of remember the melody and lyrics,
but not quite, so that keeps you busy. It always does the trick. &lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Life</category><guid>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/earworm.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2014 00:25:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Chicken Soup</title><link>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/chicken_soup.html</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="float:right" class="postimage" src="http://sef.kloninger.com/f/chicken-noodle-soup.jpg" alt="Yummy Bowl of Chicken Noodle Soup" width="40%"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My family hasn't avoided the colds that are going around now. My
way of fighting back is making chicken noodle soup.  It's not too
hard, it's satisfying, and it tastes great. &lt;a href="http://sef.kloninger.com/f/chicken_soup.pdf"&gt;The recipe&lt;/a&gt; belongs
to &lt;a href="http://peninsulaschool.org/"&gt;Peninsula School&lt;/a&gt; and gets used at our annual Craft Fair.
It's benefited from years of refinement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I add more salt. I don't do peas. I've tried with rice but it
got starchy and weird, stick with egg noodles.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Family</category><category>Life</category><guid>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/chicken_soup.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2014 01:16:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Consume vs. Produce vs. Produce Publicly</title><link>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/consume-produce-public.html</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="float:right" class="postimage" src="http://sef.kloninger.com/f/make-asl.gif" alt="\" make in american sign language width="50%"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my goals for this year is to try to produce more and consume
less. Not in the green, fixed-planetary-resources sense [1]. I
mean to make more things, ideas, contributions.  To be more creative.
Creative in literal sense of that word: creating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rands"&gt;Rands&lt;/a&gt; said it well in his post this week, 
&lt;a href="http://randsinrepose.com/archives/the-builders-high/"&gt;"The Builder's High'&lt;/a&gt;. If you haven't read it, go do so now.
I'll wait.  (and while you're at it, if you don't have him followed
or bookmarked or whatever, do that too.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I agree with pretty much everything he said in there. The good
feeling that comes from actually making soemthing. How that's
especially true now in light of the constant crush of everyone
else's creations (he called them "moments"). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making takes many forms. Since I stink at woodworking and gardening
and painting, I'll stick to the things I do enjoy, like writing and
coding and cooking. Those fit less into the traditional mold of
"building" or "making" but that's OK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to take it one step further. Here are my three categories
in value order. Numbers 1 and 2 we just spoke of, but 3 is new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consume&lt;/strong&gt;. This is watching TV, playing video games, trashy
   reading. Sure I'm going to keep doing that, but it's not energizing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Produce&lt;/strong&gt;. Cooking a meal, learning something interesting. Maybe
   even reading something intellectually challenging, but that's pushing
   it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Produce, In Public&lt;/strong&gt;. Now, this is the toughie. It's one thing to 
   do something creative, another to put yourself out there and tell 
   poeple what you did, and why. By sharing the product, by talking
   people through the choices you made to get there, you're opening
   yourself up to criticism. But why not!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is part of the reason why I &lt;a href="http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/switching-to-static.html"&gt;reworked my blog&lt;/a&gt; over the
holiday break, so I'd have a nicer platform for writing. Anything to
lower the bar to produce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] I'm not anti-green. I really appreciate the environmental
warriors out there who walk the walk with real life choices to
consume less. That's just not my bailiwick, for now at least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- vim set fo+=awn ai tw=72 --&gt;</description><category>Life</category><guid>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/consume-produce-public.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 06:51:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Seven Things You're Not Supposed to Talk About</title><link>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/201311seven-things.html</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;img class="alignright size-full wp-image-448" style="border: 0px;" alt="lucy-charliebrown" src="http://sef.kloninger.com/f/lucy-charliebrown.jpeg" width="244" height="207"&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I liked &lt;a href="http://www.thisamericanlife.org/radio-archives/episode/511/the-seven-things-youre-not-supposed-to-talk-about"&gt;this week's episode of This American Life&lt;/a&gt;. The idea is there are seven topics that you should avoid in conversation because they are always boring. &lt;strong&gt;I like this list! &lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Here is the &lt;a href="http://www.thisamericanlife.org/radio-archives/episode/511/transcript"&gt;transcript&lt;/a&gt;.  I repeat the list here.

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;How you &lt;strong&gt;slept&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Your &lt;strong&gt;period&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Health&lt;/strong&gt;. Of course if it's something serious, then that's conversation worthy, but normal sniffles, aches, and pains? No good.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Your &lt;strong&gt;dreams&lt;/strong&gt;.  Not big aspirations, this is literally what you dreamt last night&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Money&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diet&lt;/strong&gt;. What you can and can't eat.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Route&lt;/strong&gt;. How you got here, what way you're going to get home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I will endeavor to not waste all of your time droning on about any of these topics.

&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Life</category><guid>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/201311seven-things.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 03:57:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>K&amp;R C Programming, Quantum Books, Cambridge, MA</title><link>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/201309knr-c-label.html</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;img class="alignright  wp-image-433" style="border: 0px;" alt="IMG_4177" src="http://sef.kloninger.com/f/IMG_41771-231x300.jpg" width="139" height="180"&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Today in a box I came across my old K&amp;amp;R. Probably the most valuable book I've owned. My copy has been heavily used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
But the unexpected, fun thing was finding an old label on the back cover.



&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
There is a lot in there.

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter  wp-image-429" style="border: 0px;" alt="IMG_4179" src="http://sef.kloninger.com/f/IMG_4179-1024x393.jpg" width="584" height="224"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;January 1994. I had just graduated college, driven cross country with my friend &lt;a href="http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/www.linkedin.com/pub/shigeru-tanaka/0/a27/917"&gt;Shig&lt;/a&gt;, and started my first post-college job. I would have been in that job four months or so and realized that I should just stop borrowing someone else's copy (probably &lt;a href="http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/www.linkedin.com/in/larryclaman/"&gt;Larry Claman&lt;/a&gt;'s) and buy my own.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Purchased at Quantum Books, a great technical bookstore in the shadow of MIT in Cambridge, Massachusetts. It's no longer there. The bar that is there now (&lt;a style="font-style: normal;" href="http://www.themeadhall.com/"&gt;Meadhall&lt;/a&gt;) is a nice place, and I'm a big fan of beer, but it's not the same.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;According to an &lt;a style="font-style: normal;" href="http://www.bls.gov/data/inflation_calculator.htm"&gt;inflation calculator&lt;/a&gt;, $35 in 1994 is $55 today. That's expensive for a little book, especially to the twenty-two year old me.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Note the email address: quanbook@world.std.com. This was back when mom and pop dialup ISP's where what we all used, people and businesses alike. This particular one, &lt;a style="font-style: normal;" href="http://world.std.com/"&gt;Software Tool &amp;amp; Die&lt;/a&gt;, was my private email address at the time too. (Aside: they claim to be the first public dialup ISP, and I have no reason to doubt them)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
It was fun being reminded of all this stuff. So the lesson of the story: it's still worth buying books, and when you do, don't remove the labels.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Life</category><category>Technology</category><guid>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/201309knr-c-label.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 00:41:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Coding on a Flight</title><link>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/201304coding-on-a-flight.html</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;img class="alignright  wp-image-408" style="border: 0px;" alt="airplane" src="http://sef.kloninger.com/f/airplane-300x126.png" width="240" height="101"&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I'm surprised that that I like coding on flights. It's surprising because airplanes are generally hostile environments for most things, but I've found it a good place to code.



&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The obvious reason is the lack of interruptions and distractions. Usualy there is no wifi, or it is too spotty to count on. So no email or IRC or web. While I know that distractions kill flow, I never seem give myself license to unplug in normal life. I'm a manager, and being a manager means being interruptible.



&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But there's another reason. When I code unplugged, I code differently. I have to be self-sufficient. Instead of just looking things up on StackOverflow, I take 20% more time to figure it out myself. That's much more satisfying! It's just not that hard to rummage through the Django code or try things out in iPython.



&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Also it just sounds cool to say you coded something up on the flight.



&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
But thre real question is should simulate "airplane mode" when grounded.  Hmm.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Life</category><category>Technology</category><guid>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/201304coding-on-a-flight.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 05:30:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Halloween Candy Data</title><link>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/201210halloween-candy-data.html</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Update with actuals from Halloween 2012:  It was a banner year.


&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="center"&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-391" alt="halloween-2012" src="http://sef.kloninger.com/f/halloween-2012-1024x433.png" width="584" height="246"&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
You may be giving out candy later today. What can you expect? Let's look at some data.  This post summarizes the past three Halloweens.



&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="center"&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone  wp-image-378" style="border: 0px;" title="cumulative" alt="Cumulative Trick or Treaters" src="http://sef.kloninger.com/f/cumulative-1024x441.png" width="584" height="251"&gt;



&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
As you can see we live in a pretty popular neighborhood.  Each year has its own story.

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt; - our first year in our new neighborhood. We had no idea that this was such a popular trick-or-treating spot. I ran out of candy at 8:00, turned out the lights, and hid in the back of the house. Shameful.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt; - a fine year.  No complaints.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2011&lt;/strong&gt; - we moved to a new house just around the corner.  I figured the quieter street would mean fewer kids -- not so! What I didn't appreciate was the attractive power of my next door neighbor's &lt;em&gt;insane&lt;/em&gt; decorations. Luckily my wife came back with emergency supplies just in time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
And how busy do things get?  Darn busy.



&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="center"&gt;
&lt;img class="alignnone  wp-image-379" style="border: 0px;" title="rates" alt="Average and Max Trick or Treaters per Minute" src="http://sef.kloninger.com/f/rates-1024x412.png" width="584" height="234"&gt;



&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
During the busiest 15 minute period last year I was serving a kid every twenty seconds or so.  When bursting this is close to my max current candy-dispensing throughput.



&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If you come by my house this year you'll see me again, handing out candy with one hand and scribbling hash marks with the other.   I'll update the data in my &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/ccc?key=0AnpKmkglpRs5dDh3dWRmRlFVaG0yc08xU0lhTzF1NUE"&gt;public spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Life</category><guid>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/201210halloween-candy-data.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 07:19:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Managing Work-In-Progress Folders with "ls -ltr"</title><link>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/201208wip-folders-with-ls.html</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-353 alignright" style="border: 0px;" title="blog-folder-done" src="http://sef.kloninger.com/f/blog-folder-done.png" alt="" width="107" height="41"&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I've developed a nice little way to manage my work in progress folders.



&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I keep a bunch of folders around where I can stick things that are in-flight: one for home projects, one for blogs, etc. I like accumulating ideas in there, one idea per file, that I can come back to and fuss over until something is ready.



&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The folder is flypaper for ideas and notes.  My blog folder has about twenty files right now.



&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Using "ls", and relying on file and directory modification times, is a useful way to keep track of all these files.  Here's how.



&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
As projects are finished I move them into a "done" folder. This gets them out of the way.  A useful side effect is the modification time of the done directly itself gets updated.



&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The in-flight projects I care about most are the ones most recently updated: as an idea gets older it becomes less and less interesting.  When looking at this directory I use the "ls -ltr" command.  "l" means long (so you can see dates), "t" means sort by modification time, and "r" reverses that sort, so you see latest modified on the bottom.

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="center"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter  wp-image-352" style="border: 0px;" title="blog-folder-detail" src="http://sef.kloninger.com/f/blog-folder-detail.png" alt="" width="719" height="275"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The old files are at the top where I don't worry about them.  Some even scroll off the top of the screen, that's fine.  The done folder is a nice visual line for when something was last completed (say, published).  Having a separate color for directories makes this visually apparent.  And the bottom of the list are those most recently modified. Generally I work on the bottom up. Sometimes I go back to an old idea and add some notes. That bumps it to the top of the line -- it is interesting again.



&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I probably type "ls -ltr" at least 5 times an hour.  I've never aliased it since my muscle memory is so strong (but maybe I still should).



 &lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Life</category><category>Technology</category><guid>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/201208wip-folders-with-ls.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 08:56:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Danny Lewin's 42nd Birthday</title><link>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/201205danny-lewin-42nd-birthday.html</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;a href="http://www.haaretz.com/weekend/week-s-end/he-went-down-fighting-1.394969"&gt;&lt;img class="alignright size-full wp-image-216" title="Danny Lewin" src="http://sef.kloninger.com/f/danny.png" alt="" width="211" height="254"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
It's been nearly eleven years since 9/11 and I still think about &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniel_M._Lewin" target="_blank"&gt;Danny&lt;/a&gt; fairly often. Sometimes I think about the wife, sons, family, and friends that he left behind. I'm sure they miss him terribly.

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
More often, though, I think of how his life relates to mine. We were about the same age in 2001, but not peers. I was an engineer at his company, Akamai.  He was a force of nature.

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So when I think of Danny, I think about...

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;how much he did in his thirty-one years.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;all the great things that have happened to me since I was thirty-one. Two wonderful kids, amazing life experiences with my lovely wife, good career stuff.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;what a positive, can-do outlook accomplish. Both for yourself and others. Danny had that in spades.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If I was able to ask Danny how to best honor him, I think he'd tell me something amazing with urgency. He'd then kick me in the pants to go do it.

 &lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Life</category><guid>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/201205danny-lewin-42nd-birthday.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2012 19:24:14 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>