<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sef.kloninger.com (Posts about Puzzling)</title><link>https://sef.kloninger.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://sef.kloninger.com/categories/puzzling.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 16:45:52 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>The NY Times Bee Puzzle</title><link>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/timesbee/</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;How many different New York Times Spelling Bee puzzles are there? Or more
precisely, how many combinations of seven letters can be used to build Bee-type
puzzles?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out &lt;strong&gt;7,742 different seven letter combinations&lt;/strong&gt; can be used to
generate Bee-style puzzles. There are more puzzles themseves based on what
letter is chosen for the middle spot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The majority of letter choices, about 62%, have just one pangram. That's lower
than I expected, actually. It's not that uncommon to have two or three pangrams,
which happens about about 25% of the time, and nearly four out of ten puzzles
will have more than one pangram. The full output is &lt;a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/sefk/timesbee/master/timesbee.out"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, the output of this
&lt;a href="https://github.com/sefk/timesbee"&gt;program&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch out for the combination &lt;code&gt;einprst&lt;/code&gt;. If this one ever comes up, good
luck finding all twenty-seven of its pangrams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Bee Puzzle&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="float:right" class="postimage" src="https://sef.kloninger.com/f/timesbee.png" alt="Example Times Bee Puzzle" width="40%"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Bee puzzle has seven letters with one "special" letter in the middle. Make as
many words as You can find with at least four letters, using only the letters
given, but it has to use the center letter. Proper nouns aren't allowed. Every
puzzle has at least one &lt;strong&gt;pangram&lt;/strong&gt;, a word that uses all letters — this
example's is &lt;em&gt;amphibian&lt;/em&gt;. Wikipedia cites &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frank_Longo"&gt;Frank Longo&lt;/a&gt; as the Bee's creator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://nytbee.com/"&gt;nytbee.com&lt;/a&gt; has more today's puzzle and some interesting stats about these
puzzles in general. They don't seem to be affiliated with the NY Times but that
seem to be OK and is's a nice site.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Family</category><category>Puzzling</category><guid>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/timesbee/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>