<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sef.kloninger.com (Posts about Tech)</title><link>https://sef.kloninger.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://sef.kloninger.com/categories/tech.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 19:50:17 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>AI Is Good At Janitorial Work</title><link>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/gemini-claude-cleanup/</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="float:right" class="postimage" src="https://sef.kloninger.com/f/gemini-claude-cleanup.png" alt="Claude Code on the left, Gemini on the right" width="60%"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's been nice having AI tools at the ready for cleanup work. You know, those
tasks that require a little program or script. Sure you can write it yourself,
but it won't be fun, and it'll take some time, so instead you just don't bother
and it doesn't get done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of just knocking this out I decided this would be a fun one to try with
the two tools I'm using the most these days, &lt;strong&gt;Gemini&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Claude&lt;/strong&gt;. I can't
really call this a proper bakeoff, since it's just those two and it's not an
especially hard task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And the result? Both did well but Gemini did a little better.&lt;/strong&gt; Gemini got it
right on the first try; Claude had two bugs that were easy to find and fix.
Claude was a little nicer to work with and produced a nicer description of the
solution. Aside from that, the end product was identical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Task&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to clean up the some of the old files backing this blog. I migrated the
site from Wordpress to Nikola in 2013. Even back then I &lt;a href="https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/switching-to-static.md"&gt;complained
about&lt;/a&gt; the crufty file format, but couldn't be
bothered to fix it then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prompt describes in a fair bit of detail what I wanted done. Probably too
much detail. It's down at the bottom of this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way to see what they did is to just look at the resulting commits:
&lt;a href="https://github.com/sefk/sefk.github.io/commit/4a91a57dc965b1e77c05fafbc05fa14f1a293c7f"&gt;Gemini&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://github.com/sefk/sefk.github.io/commit/78cee0789d98677c5298df543e895d7e2002ff72"&gt;Claude&lt;/a&gt;. They're pretty similar. I asked both to save
their work in a &lt;code&gt;migration_scripts&lt;/code&gt; subdirectory, including a it's own summary
of the work and full log.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For both tools I pay the $20/month that gives me access to reasonable token
limits and good production models -- Gemini 3 and Sonnet 4.6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Thoughts on Claude&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't describe the problem as "Wordpress-style naming" but Claude sussed that
out. Honestly I'd forgotten that was the source of the problem. Nice!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like that Claude inserted comments in the configuration file without being
asked to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite being told to test, there were two bugs that I had to find.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of redirects broken. I pointed the problem out and it did more thorough
  testing using &lt;code&gt;curl&lt;/code&gt; and found the problem. The new format was what Gemini
  came up with in the first pass (luck? smarts?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A missing newline between the metadata and the body caused the hero images
  to be dropped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="side by side view showing bug" src="https://sef.kloninger.com/f/cleanup-missing-hero.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Thoughts on Gemini&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven't used the Gemini CLI as much by this point. It seems to have borrowed
much of it's UI and flow from Claude code (slash commands, asking questions as
it goes) so it's familiar. It's really nice to use, just a smidgen less mature
and polished than Gemini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I preferred Claude's writeup a little so I went with that one. But Gemini wins
the prize for nailing the task on the first try!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Usage&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really liked how Claude shows how much of it's context window is used via the
&lt;code&gt;/context&lt;/code&gt; command. I had a harder time getting this kind of thing out of
Gemini, and even when I did it was harder to grok.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I couldn't tell with either if I'm getting close to any global usage limits. I
should hope not, this wasn't a very big job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Claude &lt;code&gt;/context&lt;/code&gt; Output&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Claude context window usage" src="https://sef.kloninger.com/f/claude-context.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Gemini &lt;code&gt;/stats model&lt;/code&gt; Output&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Gemini "stats for nerds"' src="https://sef.kloninger.com/f/gemini-context.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Prompt&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both started with this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="code"&gt;&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;First read DEV.md for context about this web site.

In the posts subdirectory are many files that follow an old 
naming convention.  Please convert them all to the new file
naming convention.

The old convention has files of the format YYYYMM&amp;lt;slug&amp;gt;.SUFFIX,
where YYYY is the year, MM is the month, and SUFFIX is html or
meta. &amp;lt;slug&amp;gt; is the short form of the the title, and should match
the "slug" field in the metadata

To convert to the new convention

1. Drop the YYYYMM file prefix

2. Combine the "html" and "meta" files into one markdown file
   with a "md" suffix. The contents of "meta" are at the top of
   the file as an HTML comment

3. Add redirects so the old names can still be served. Add tuples
   in the REDIRECTIONS of conf.py

Use the `nikola build` and `nikola serve` commands to test your
work. Make sure all old URL's still function. Make sure pages
look the same. Make sure tags still work.

Do not commit changes. Do not push to production.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also checked in a &lt;a href="https://github.com/sefk/sefk.github.io/blob/dev/DEV.md"&gt;&lt;code&gt;DEV.md&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; file that described the purpose, directory
layout, and some constraints. Again, maybe overkill, but I figured this isn't
the last time I'll be asking one of these tools to help me futz with this site.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>AI</category><category>Tech</category><guid>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/gemini-claude-cleanup/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Yeah, I Did Some Vibe Coding Too</title><link>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/daleks/</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;This is a story about my recent experience Vibe Coding. The work itself isn't
impressive and this writeup isn't different than the many gee-whiz posts you see
these days. I didn't do &lt;a href="https://mastodon.social/@stroughtonsmith/116014270900193494"&gt;three apps in a day&lt;/a&gt;. But I wanted to write up my
experience, mostly to give me an excuse to tell an old tyme programming story
from the 1900's.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://sef.kloninger.com/daleks"&gt;
&lt;img style="float:right" class="postimage" src="https://sef.kloninger.com/f/daleks-2026.png" alt="Screenshot of my recent Daleks game" width="50%"&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Today, 2026&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I'm &lt;a href="https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/leaving-google/"&gt;on a break&lt;/a&gt; I'm taking a &lt;a href="https://continuingstudies.stanford.edu/courses/detail/20252_TECH-42"&gt;Vibe Coding class&lt;/a&gt;. It's a fun excuse to
play with some new toys, and it's well taught, and I like doing things with my
friend Jane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One interesting tidbit: the first day of class, February 3, 2026, was one year
and one day after "vibe coding" itself was coined via &lt;a href="https://x.com/karpathy/status/1886192184808149383?lang=en"&gt;tweet&lt;/a&gt;. That name seems
to have stuck, for the time being at least. On &lt;a href="https://atp.fm/678"&gt;last week's ATP&lt;/a&gt; they said that
by this time next year this will probably just be called "coding" and I bet
they're right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway our week one assignment was to code up a game. &lt;strong&gt;In about two hours and
$10&lt;/strong&gt; I had a something up and running. I spent another couple of hours futzing
with version control, documentation, and hosting. But that's it! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's pretty basic, and not all that much fun, but you can &lt;a href="https://sef.kloninger.com/daleks"&gt;play it here&lt;/a&gt;. It's
hosted on Github pages, just like this blog. The code and construction notes are
in &lt;a href="https://github.com/sefk/daleks"&gt;checked in&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my first experience with &lt;a href="https://replit.com/"&gt;Replit&lt;/a&gt;. It's impressive and fun. This was
what was recommended for the class and the good folks at Replit were nice enough
to give us all $30 in credits, which I had plenty to spare. Most of my comrades
presented apps that were fancier than mind with 3d graphics, sound, and more
interactive game play. some also said though that they ended up spending much
more than I did, so YMMV on costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One interesting part was dealing with integration. To get their code deployed
onto my personal website site required wiring up a GitHub workflow, which I'd
never done before. No problem, Replit took care of that too. Then I asked
&lt;a href="https://geminicli.com/"&gt;Gemini&lt;/a&gt; to get local hosting running. When I hit a permissions problem and a
crash I had to resist the urge to copy paste the error messages into a search
boxes and Stack Overflow, like I've done for years. Instead I asked Gemini to
debug and sort this out for itself and it did straight away. Pretty great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.macintoshrepository.org/3913-daleks"&gt;
&lt;img style="float:right" class="postimage" src="https://sef.kloninger.com/f/daleks-1984.jpeg" alt="Original Daleks game from 1984" width="45%"&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Forty Years Ago, 1985&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why'd I pick this weird old &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robots_%28BSD_game%29"&gt;chase game&lt;/a&gt;? Well, that's the more fun and
nostalgic part of the story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was fourteen years old, I spent the summer hand-coding a video game. I'd
gone to a family gathering and my older cousin Erik brought his Mac from
college. It was the first I'd seen a Mac and fell in love. I thought the
Daleks game he had running on it was so cool. The screenshot on the right
is from that Classic Mac website of that game that I found online, and is
exactly how I remember it looked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon return to Fresno I got to work. I spent most of the rest of that summer
writing a clone of Daleks on my Apple //e. All hand-coded 6502 opcodes and twos
complement math for branch offsets by hand (I didn't have an assembler), in
pencil on graph paper. The hardest part was getting smooth animation working,
since the Apple //e "hi res" &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apple_II_graphics"&gt;graphics system&lt;/a&gt; was super quirky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took about two months to get it working. It's the first time I can remember
being in a flow state and I loved it. It was my first "real program" and began
my lifelong love of computers.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>AI</category><category>Tech</category><category>War Stories</category><guid>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/daleks/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Thanks, Daisy Disk</title><link>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/daisy-disk/</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="float:right" class="postimage" src="https://sef.kloninger.com/f/daisy-disk-full.png" alt="Screenshot of Daisy Disk with a disk nearly full" width="50%"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I've been beguiled by my local disk being almost full. This is on my
everyday M3 MacBook Air running the latest Tahoe 26.2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For years I've used &lt;a href="https://daisydiskapp.com/"&gt;Daisy Disk&lt;/a&gt; to debug space issues like this, it's great.
In this case it showed the problem, but wasn't able to narrow down what the
problem was nor remove it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not have any success through the normal means ("Googling around"), I wrote the
developer of Daisy Disk, &lt;a href="https://daisydiskapp.com/about/"&gt;Oleg&lt;/a&gt;. They explained the problem and suggested a
workaround. It worked like a champ! I included the explanation below and
screenshots showing before and after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to say thanks to Oleg for their help. And this is a nice opportunity to
say thank you to indie developers in general who are often so helpful sharing
their expertise. What a wonderful and important part of our community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oleg's explanation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
This error has recently been reported by a few other users as well, and our
investigation shows that it's caused by a new bug in macOS, introduced in one
of its recent updates. (It didn't happen before). The symptom is exactly like
in your case - a Time Machine snapshot becomes damaged for unknown reason, and
it cannot be deleted in the normal way - not only in DaisyDisk, but also not
in Terminal, using the tmutil command-line tool. Moreover, the tmutil tool
doesn't even list the damaged snapshot. It becomes almost entirely lost, while
it still consumes disk space.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We have found the following workaround solution. Please launch the system's Disk
Utility (/Applications/Utilities/Disk Utility.app) and in the left sidebar,
select your data volume, likely called "Macintosh HD - Data". Note that there
will also be another volume called "Macintosh HD" (without "Data"), but you
should select specifically "Macintosh HD - Data". Then select the View \&amp;gt; Show
APFS Snapshots menu command. In the lower part of the window, you will see the
damaged Time Machine snapshot in the list. Please select it and then click the
"-" (minus) button at the bottom to delete it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And screenshots showing the before and after. Note the two broken snapshots in
the list below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Disk utility showing disk almost full" src="https://sef.kloninger.com/f/daisy-disk-before.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Disk utility showing disk back to normal" src="https://sef.kloninger.com/f/daisy-disk-after.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Appreciation</category><category>Tech</category><guid>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/daisy-disk/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:00:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Data Is Worth Preserving</title><link>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/data-preservation/</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="float:right" class="postimage" src="https://sef.kloninger.com/f/drp-logo.jpg" alt="Logo for the Data Rescue Project" width="30%"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Governments should produce &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Public_good"&gt;public goods&lt;/a&gt;, like navigation aids and roads. That
seems like a reasonable thing to expect of a functioning government, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I consider data a public good too. We all benefit from accurate maps,
thorough measurements of the natural world, and trustworthy economic data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which is why it was I was so upset when I heard how the the current US
administration has been on a tear to &lt;strong&gt;actually remove data&lt;/strong&gt;. All through 2025,
websites were taking down and datasets were taken offline. This &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2025_United_States_government_online_resource_removals"&gt;Wikipedia page&lt;/a&gt;
catalogs what's been happening, and this report by the &lt;a href="https://www.amstat.org/policy-and-advocacy/the-nation's-data-at-risk-meeting-american's-information-needs-for-the-21st-century"&gt;American Statistical
Association&lt;/a&gt; goes into more depth about what's been happening and its
implications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response the &lt;a href="https://www.datarescueproject.org/"&gt;Data Rescue Project&lt;/a&gt; sprang into action. They're a group of
concerned academics, librarians, and citizens who have been copying and
cataloging datasets so they aren't lost. The &lt;a href="https://www.datarescueproject.org/press/"&gt;project's press page&lt;/a&gt; has links to
many articles and presentations that describe their work and its impact. Last
November I saw a call for volunteers for DRP on a mailing list of ex-Googlers
and was eager to help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Homeland Infrastructure Foundation-Level Data (HIFLD)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's worth describing a bit about the particular dataset I actually worked on:
Homeland Infrastructure Foundation-Level Data (HIFLD). It's a good case study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HIFLD is a collection of maps. Maps of basic stuff, like roads, levees, river
depth charts, locations of military bases. Beyond just being good maps, a big
part of HIFLD's value is helping to make sure everyone uses &lt;em&gt;the same maps&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So HIFLD is mostly curating data. Most of the data comes from other agencies
(USGS, Army Corps of Engineers, Census Bureau) and HIFLD brings it together and
provides it in a trustworthy, central place. Well, I should say "provided"
because in September the &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/gis/comments/1lkol3s/sad_news_hifld_open_to_be_discontinued_by_sept_30/"&gt;government stopped providing it&lt;/a&gt;. The story is well
told in this good &lt;a href="https://projectgeospatial.org/geospatial-frontiers/the-rise-power-and-uncertain-future-of-americas-open-infrastructure-data"&gt;article on Project Geospatial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where the Data Rescue Project comes in. DRP volunteers immediately
scooped up the data and kept in temporary storage. Then they organized a bucket
brigade of volunteers to categorize and put &lt;a href="https://www.datalumos.org/datalumos/search/studies?q=hifld%20open"&gt;snapshots&lt;/a&gt; into long-term storage.
Importantly, this was coupled with metadata to ensure they're findable later.
That's the part I worked on, uploading and entering metadata. We met our goal of
getting all of HIFLD "rescued" by year's end. &lt;a href="https://libguides.brown.edu/prf.php?account_id=276524"&gt;Frank Donnelly&lt;/a&gt;, the project
manager, wrote up a nice &lt;a href="https://www.datarescueproject.org/hifld-data-saved/"&gt;summary&lt;/a&gt; of what we did and how. For my piece I relied
on a nice Selenium driver, written by another volunteer, to create over a
hundred projects (&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/dVadwqbJoSs"&gt;screen recording&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just one of many DRP efforts. Check out their &lt;a href="https://www.datarescueproject.org/data-rescue-tracker/"&gt;tracker&lt;/a&gt; to see the
breadth of work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I'm proud of this project, I keep reminding myself that we're playing
defense. Having a one-time snapshot isn't nearly as good as having the
government actually do its job. Which is why we need to keep demanding better
leadership and a return to effective government. Assert your rights and
&lt;a href="https://www.nokings.org/"&gt;protest&lt;/a&gt;!   ❌ 👑.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Civics</category><category>Life</category><category>Tech</category><guid>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/data-preservation/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>