<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sef.kloninger.com (Posts about Tech)</title><link>https://sef.kloninger.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://sef.kloninger.com/categories/tech.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 05:07:46 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Naming Is Hard</title><link>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/naming/</link><dc:creator>Sef Kloninger</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lenna"&gt;&lt;img style="float:right" class="postimage" src="https://sef.kloninger.com/f/lena.png" alt="Photo of Lena Forsén" width="40%"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a story about how hard it is to come up with a good name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was in 2013. I was part of a team building a &lt;a href="https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/201207on-line-education/"&gt;system for online
education&lt;/a&gt; at Stanford. We &lt;a href="https://engineering.stanford.edu/news/stanford-launches-class2go-open-source-platform-online-classes"&gt;launched&lt;/a&gt; a nice little site,
Class2Go, with a small team in a few months. It worked well and
supported the basic features of an online course: videos, assessments,
auth, reporting. We decided to keep it going and worked on it for
another year, expanding the covered use cases and taking on more
classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But even from the beginning the name &lt;em&gt;Class2Go&lt;/em&gt; felt a bit off. Our
original aim was to enable offline &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Massive_open_online_course"&gt;MOOC&lt;/a&gt; students, people trying
to take classes offline or in poorly-connected places But we ended
up pivoting away from the offline use case to more standard
hosted-course features. It became a little multi-tenant CMS with a
small database for auth, assessment results, and some basic analytics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided to rebrand. Someone knew a naming consultant, presumably
an alum, and soon enough we had an expert on board. They were really
interesting to work with. After understanding the platform's goals
and features, they generated hundreds of candidate names. Each was
vetting for domain name availability and copyright conflicts. The
consultant was good at their job, bringing us something like a hundred
candidate names (I wish I still had that list).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One name caught everyone's attention: &lt;strong&gt;Tindra&lt;/strong&gt;. It's a Swedish
word that means "sparkle" or "twinkle." It's evocative and easy to
say. It also happens to be a woman's name, but not a particularly
common one we were told. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, &lt;code&gt;tindra.com&lt;/code&gt; was available! In 2013 short and catchy
domain names were getting hard to come The &lt;a href="https://newgtldprogram.icann.org/"&gt;new gTLD program&lt;/a&gt; had
only just been approved in 2012, and &lt;code&gt;.com&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;.org&lt;/code&gt; were pretty
crowded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem was that if you Googled "tindra," the top result was a
Swedish adult film actress! Not good. Maybe with enough SEO juice,
over time, we would have overtaken that. But on launch day, that's
not the association you want to have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ended up punting on the problem and going with a generic name,
&lt;strong&gt;Stanford Online&lt;/strong&gt;. It got the job done, but felt like a missed
opportunity. We later merged with edX and &lt;a href="https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/leaving-stanford/"&gt;I found another job&lt;/a&gt;.
Eventually the team re-branded the site with the name &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://online.stanford.edu/lagunita-learning-platform"&gt;Lagunita&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;,
the name of the lake on campus, which they're still using today. I
like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I admit I still have a thing for Tindra.  The name, not the actress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Postscript: &lt;code&gt;tindra.com&lt;/code&gt; still doesn't seem to be used for anything
today. It looks to just be parked by a German domain registrar.
Google results don't seem to be a problem. Maybe it's available for
something interesting?&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Education</category><category>Tech</category><category>War Stories</category><guid>https://sef.kloninger.com/posts/naming/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>