<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>sef.kloninger.com (Tech)</title><link>http://sef.kloninger.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://sef.kloninger.com/categories/tech.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2013 00:37:13 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>nikola</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Airmail FTW</title><link>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/201312airmail.html</link><description>&lt;img class="alignright  wp-image-454" style="border: 0px;" alt="airmail" src="http://sef.kloninger.com/f/airmail.png" width="179" height="179"&gt;Finally a thick-client email program that seems to have stuck. So far I am really liking &lt;a href="http://airmailapp.com/"&gt;Airmail&lt;/a&gt;.

&lt;p&gt;
For years I've flipped between various Mac fat clients and the GMail web interface. The web interface keeps winning:

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Outstanding search&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Great keyboard shortcuts (go Vi!)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Very good use of screen real estate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
But the killer is the reliance on a rock-solid Internet connection, and GMail's own slowdowns. Even though there is an offline mode, it is such a downgrade it's not worth using. So if you need to use offline you're in bad shape; same if you're on a slow or lossy connection, or if GMail is having a bad day.  Sadly, that's pretty often these days.



&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Airmail is cheap (&lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/airmail/id573171375?mt=12"&gt;$1.99 in the App Store&lt;/a&gt;) and super featureful. It coexists well with GMail's paradigm (archive vs. delete, threading includes sent items, drafts). Great configuration options. Visually pleasing. Robust.



&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
There are really only three places where it has fallen short for me:

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;I miss GMail's tabs. Those are still the best way to filter mail, and I was impressed with how well that feature worked and quickly became natural.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Search. Airmail's isn't bad, but nothing is as good at this as Google's own.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Gmail (with Chrome) has a great feature where you can drop in a picture and it is resized to look good.  Lacking that I now have to manually resize my giant retina-display screenshots.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
So-long to &lt;a href="http://sparrowmailapp.com/"&gt;Sparrow&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/osx/apps/#mail"&gt;Mail.app&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://mailplaneapp.com/"&gt;Mailplane&lt;/a&gt;. Or until someone does really nails &lt;a href="https://www.mailpile.is/"&gt;self-hosting&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Tech</category><guid>http://sef.kloninger.com/posts/201312airmail.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 20:10:50 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>